[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
howdy duty my cat dogs welcome
to the junkyard love podcast real quick
before we get poppin
the first 30 minutes or so of this
episode is in regards to
the event that is premiering this
weekend that we're posting this
september 19th
if you're listening to the after feel
free to skip through that or if you want
to hear how we set up an event and how
we made this
uh virtual stream happen it's all good
info
um toasty explains kind of what we get
going on but if you're here for the rest
of it feel free to skip around and
listen to what you'd like in this
episode we kind of talk about
a lot of the dj creator creative process
kind of the mind behind things
substances suicide depression
our experiences tosi's experiences being
a dj for 25 plus
years the whole thing's packed full of
greatness so
i hope you enjoy uh if you would like to
watch our
live stream on saturday if you're
listening to this beforehand
we would love to have you hope you have
a good time enjoy the podcast take care
of yourself
and we're live
are we broadcasting live we are
broadcasting live like
like glow-in-the-dark broadcasting live
yes oh perfect
live but later that's that was the thing
is like explaining to people
wait so it's not a live stream but it's
just a stream and right like their brain
is like
doesn't com compute yeah it was uh yeah
no it's no we're broadcasting there's a
slight broadcast delay
yeah but having that extra time i mean
just like running
uh because i've done some live stream
well i've done one big live stream
um for the texas thing right yeah i was
out in texas
and uh that one was was it's weird
because it had the stress
of a live show
yeah uh like you stood like the jitters
like right before it goes because it's
like if you mess up it's live people
right
people still hear it but uh it is it's
it's weird when there's no crowd
yeah but i'm glad that we did it the way
that we did it for glow in the dark so
ladies and gentlemen welcome to the
junkyard love podcast today we have my
friend brian on
and uh we want to talk about glow in
dark first and foremost this is an event
that we just did we uh
shot all the footage and um did all the
things
we set it all up and
we did it yeah and it's done yeah but uh
brian took a lot time
a lot of time to edit it and put it all
together so
on september 19th we have a show and
it's edited
nicely and it looks real good it sounds
good too it sounds real good oh yeah
um okay so
brian i do want to get into your
background
um we have plans to talk about some
mental health stuff we want to talk
about some suicide stuff just
just some real talks um that we've
experienced in our in our life
um being dj's you've been dj for quite
some time you have a lot more years on
me
um but we'll start it out with glow in
the dark so
what is glow-in-the-dark all right so
so
last time that we that we had a podcast
we had kelly our good friend
he was on with us and we were talking
about
at the end of the podcast you know later
stages in your dji career
and wanting to be able to play you know
the music that
that you like that you love that you
want to share with people and as as djs
um i'm going to be honest you know the
normal working
working dj isn't always playing 100 the
music that they
really love or that they want to share
with people and so
you know what we talked about was a lot
of these guys that are
getting long in the tooth you know i've
been doing it doing this for 25 plus
years
um they start they start throwing their
own night
they start putting their own party
together they start
building um something that obviously
you know they're the the center
entertainer for
um but they allows them to
start exposing people to music that that
they love and start sharing it and
and if it's if it's huge that's great
if it's not huge you know then then
you're still
having a good time and and you're still
loving it and so glow-in-the-dark for me
um you know i worked i'm i'm really good
friends with
the owners of a couple of venues in town
and
kind of pitched the idea to them saying
hey i wanna
you know it started out as a black light
party and so
it was something unique um and
so we we threw the first one and and
it was very mainstream um top 40 hip-hop
you know the music really didn't differ
from
what the venue would normally be playing
and so
everybody loved it um the staff um
really loved it um you know tips were
astronomical uh the owners loved it the
the sales were great
staff loved i mean the the guests love
it um
it just went over really well so i got
permission to do another one
so the next one you know i um
i anything that i do
i want to make sure that the next time
that i do it um that i'm
challenging myself in some small way i
love that about you
and not that i have to be you know the
best
at um something but i definitely
um don't want to just do the same thing
that i did last time
um last time was successful um that's
great
um but to to basically hang our hat on
oh yeah we you know we did so well and
there were so many people that came
through the door last time
that's not really what i'm about so and
the second one that we did
um i i pushed um music programming a
little bit more
um wasn't as mainstream um
had uh kelly um he he came and did uh
basically the stage manager slash roadie
for me helped me set up
we brought in more equipment more
lighting more complex lighting
um more than just quote black lights um
more sound um so then the third one um i
said you know how can we improve on it
because
the first two were just the quote dj
toasty show
um i said you know let's let's pull
people in that
that um i think are good um for the
event
that can bring in energy and so um we
booked kelly
and kelly um i did an opening set kelly
did did a mid-set
kind of warmed up and then i did a
closing set and then we brought in way
more lights and way more sound and
and so that's kind of where we're at and
so then before kovid
um we had one scheduled for april it was
you know supposed to be quote
my birthday party um we had an
opportunity to
link with you and so that was
that was my opportunity i mean when we
were going to do
way more lights and we were going to
bring in professional lasers and all
that piece you know the production value
but
allowed me then to
work with multiple artists of
different skill sets and backgrounds
and you know how to basically make the
night with
multiple people rather than just me
quote controlling
from start to finish and so that's a
skill set that
that i hadn't used for quite a while you
know i used to be a music director and i
would
work with djs and you know let them know
what to play and
but um it had been a while since i had
worked with multiple
talented individuals that were actually
performing
and basically bringing them into what my
vision was and the cool thing is is that
you know you me and kelly
we've had quite a long conversations um
you know over
over beers over the past couple months
and you know we've shared tidbits
between each other of
where i where i'm hoping that
glow-in-the-dark will
will go at some point so covet hit
um and we had to postpone
uh the april show and um
so we postponed it and we postponed it
to september and it wasn't that big of a
deal for me
you know i it wasn't the end of the
world but then obviously covet
extended a lot longer than than we were
anticipating
and um so about july
you know i was i was doing some live
streaming uh stuff like most djs
just be able to get the creative juices
going and
um i was i was actually watching um in
zombiax
streams so they're doing you know
virtual edc
and virtual beyond wonderland and
virtual
you know hard fest i mean they're just
going all out
and they're you know they're kicking ass
um red cube out of portland you know
they're doing live streams and they're
you know they have it at 45 east and so
they got all the lights and the lasers
going
and and
it was about the middle of july and you
know my my wife who is
we've been married for 15 years um very
supportive of
of all my creative endeavors um she said
you know
you should you should do a live stream
you should have you know you and kelly
and jake because that's who you're gonna
plan and
we'll do a couple of lights you know and
we'll we'll make it happen
well that that really um was the wrong
thing to say because
because she planted that seed and i said
yeah you're right
we should do that and also and it turned
into
you know i'm getting a variance meaning
a license to be able to run
high-level concert level lasers
we upped the budget
on the lighting rig out of portland we
we so
up up the lasers up the lighting rig
we had kelly and you and then i said
well how are we going to capture it you
know and i didn't want to
i didn't want to do it live because i
just saw that all the challenges
of doing a live event a live full
production crew
to run everything yeah and there's and
there's three of us and one of us
would always be djing so it's really
only two people running it
and so my concern was is that something
would happen
like we would put on this production and
we would have hopefully
you know being honest 50 to maybe 75
people watching it right
and then something would happen and if
something happened and it was you know
something that jake
who's djing is the only person that
could fix it it just
to me it didn't feel like a recipe for
success
and honestly i'm gonna tell you and and
i know red cube is doing their stuff
live
i don't think insomniac is doing their
stuff live yeah are they saying they're
doing it either
no oh so they they aren't saying that
they are
they are broadcasting they have changed
a little bit
and i believe that they are doing what
we did which was
they have a warehouse they have a bunch
of djs
they roll them through it might be four
o'clock in the afternoon really
and they're doing all of their post
editing and then they're posting it
later
so um i just wanted a really good
product
and something that i could you know as
the producer of it be proud
and so i just said we're gonna have to
record it well
then that opened up a whole new
challenge because i've done lighting
before
i've i've used high-end blazers before
um
you know i've done sound before i've
done live streaming before
and so um it opened up
a whole new challenge that i'd never
used
um mirrorless um
4k high definition cameras like you use
for shooting documentaries and you know
all the recap videos that you see from
these huge festivals
you know that level of of camera work
that they're doing
and so um i reached out to a friend
um that is a really big
documentaries videographer he's got
a couple sundance appearances and
multitude of awards and couple tv shows
on on amazon
um his name's anthony gainer very
good long term or very i've known him
for a lot of years and
and i knew him from when i was in
portland doing the music director
um piece so he kind of just guided me a
little bit and then
and the one piece of advice that i can i
can give people is that
if you're going to somebody to ask them
for help
don't the the analogy that i always use
is don't go to them with a box of broken
parts and slide it across the desk and
say fix this for me
right um when when you're talking to
people that
are very good at what they do
and they don't have you know maybe a lot
of time or you don't have a lot of money
let's say you know in my case i didn't
have a lot of money in the in the budget
to be able to go to him and say
hey can you tell me how to do all this
you know this guy's
his consulting rate is 100 an hour and
i'm asking him for a bunch of free time
and so the way that i approached it with
him was that i did about
two months of research like this what i
want to do
how i want to do it these are what this
is what reddit's saying this is what
youtube videos are saying
you know and i just kind of made a
mental checklist and wrote everything
out
and i went to him and i said this is
this is uh what i want to do
and this is all the research that i've
done and this were
the direction i think i want to go is
this correct
and are there any blind spots that that
i'm not thinking about
and i said and i will gladly i jokingly
said buy you a cup of coffee right
well he came back and and he basically
redlined you know or checkmarked
all of the stuff he didn't have to do
any of the thinking right and he came
back within
30 minutes you know he's like and don't
forget about this and you could try this
and
and if you have any questions let me
know and by the way don't worry about it
but
my normal rate's 100 an hour but you
know
well i gave him a hundred dollars for
his time
and um so through the process of
planning for the event
i hit him up multiple times i think um
ended up being three times total and i
gave him i didn't give him a hundred
dollars
you know the second time i think it was
like 25 because it was
a text conversation right right um and
and had i gone to him and said you know
hey i want to do this
tell me how you do you in
in a 30 minute email um i don't think it
would have been as successful so
anyway we we got through that and
um so we we ended up getting all the
equipment in
and um at the time it was just going to
be
jake you know myself and and kelly
and i said you know to myself if if we
are
if we're taking all this time and effort
and and money i mean there was
there was a rental cost to it um
why not instead of just having three
artists have
multiple artists and so you know i
i tapped kelly and i said kelly i said
this is you know i
i really need quality people i need you
know
a good dj or good artist on top of the
three that we have now
and just one it was twofold one i wanted
i wanted more
involvement because we're gonna have it
all set up so why not record more people
right
two if they were from out of town
because
we're from southwest washington right
it's it's a little bit different because
if we're doing an event southwest
washington and we're
trying to get our homies to go to a show
you know
they've got maybe a 20-minute drive max
right so it's very regional but now
we've gone to doing a streaming event
like anybody could watch it anybody you
know
anybody in the world if they wanted to
and so
um you don't have any friends
tell tell anybody tell your grandma
she'll like it maybe not the second set
but for sexual
so the
you know it was it was a marketing piece
as well i wanted to get more people
involved so more people would be
talking about it of course and and more
people regionally talking about it
so kelly came up with um he's like oh we
need to you know i'm talking with these
guys for real
and i'm like cool what's a sonic cloud
link so you know i i
listen to it and and i i i
stalk them you know and they're like oh
they you know they they did
30 so uh opening party and they've done
this
and they've got a couple trucks that
they produced out right i'm like that's
cool
yeah let's do it right i mean if if they
aren't
100 like legit on the dj aspect but you
know they've got
500 followers on on soundcloud and and
they've put out some pretty cool trap
music right i'm like let's do it
they seem like cool guys right so we get
them on board
and then and then we have um you
actually reached out to brian
um yeah edastra and um
you guys all went to school together or
at least you went to mark morris right
yeah i think he's a few years younger
than me yeah but
but kelly's good friends with them too
yeah and you're good friends with them
and he
he's a producer and i didn't think
anything of it you know
he he got put in the fold and
and you know i basically had to sell it
to him i'm like
he's like what you know what are we
doing it for and i said well i said you
know
there's no money uh because all the
money's wrapped up in production
i said you know they're deep down
um there's a whole save our stages.com
movement going on where the federal
government
hasn't provided a lot of financial
support for many industries
but including the the live music
industry and event venues
um and so not so much
benefiting um me directly as
as a event producer but
you know i'm thinking as a consumer um
if 45 east and portland goes away if q
nightclub
up in seattle all these venues all the
venues that have any shows in seven
months right
you can only hang on for so long um
seriously
and so for me it allowed me to then
um kind of dovetail that into well let's
let's promote save our stages.com
save our stages is um a
national effort from the nas national
um national independent
uh venue association neva niva
and our stages.com is is their
push and their grass roots lobbying to
our legislators to provide financial
assistance to
venues that have been closed for the
past seven months um
and so that affects roseland you know
it's just not edm
uh venues uh roseland doug fur
mississippi studios um you know there's
there's a lot of members that are part
of this that
they're not having touring acts coming
through they're not having
you you know you can't have you can't
have shows right now and so
they have zero venue revenue coming in
so um that's one of our goals with the
event is to be able to
raise awareness for that but what i told
brian
was that because he's like what are we
doing it for
i mean not not sean like that he just
wanted to understand where i was coming
from
and so he um i said you know
save our stages.com we're trying to
raise awareness for that
i said honestly um uh kelly jake and i
um it's to be able to release some
creativity
whether or not it's from playing music
to you know me being challenged
um to kelly and jake being challenged
to do
production pieces maybe that we haven't
done before um
so it was um
you know it's i went went to brian and i
was honest with them that you know
there's no budget for for artists
nobody's getting paid there's no
we haven't monetized this there's no
plan of monetizing it um
here's how what we're spending on on the
production it's going to be
you know what i think is probably um
within our means top notch
um and and i think it's going to be
really fun
and and i would love to have you be a
part of it
um and so he he definitely was um
on board it was it was cool so we
um it was two weekends ago wasn't it
yeah
two weekends ago so um the last weekend
in august
uh we did a load in um
of equipment on on friday um all the
stuff
got shipped in for the lasers and 4k
cameras and and all the production and
gimbals and
and and all that and we got to figure
out how to film
with 4k cameras and um you know it was
me jake and kelly
we did all the pre-production work um
[Music]
and i i am
i am beyond the moon i keep talking to
kelly and jake about
um what the final product was
you know we have it is it is edited uh
it's edited and sensed that um we
recorded the dj set
it is the actual dj set um so there are
through and through through and through
you know there you can if you're a dj
you're going to listen to it you're like
oh they missed you know they missed that
transition
you know i have a couple flubs on mine
um it's we were actually djing there
wasn't any yeah
it's it's it's very uh it's very live um
and it's very raw
and i'm and i'm super excited about
every artist that was
involved um it we were talking about
this before we got started
um you know you you have that that level
of production
and lighting lasers and it looks great
on film and it
had we had any artists or dj that maybe
needed a little bit more time practicing
you know
i'm i feel that every artist
that that you're going to watch this
weekend
um or on replays if we can get it you
know online
to not get kicked off twitch and youtube
oh my gosh yeah we'll talk about that
too
um i i think that people are just going
to be blown away
the the entire package is is great
um considering that you know on a
production level
um jake kelly and i are are um
i won't say we're amateurs i mean we
have definitely experienced in the field
but but we're not doing big festivals
yeah and we're not part of the
insomniac crew you know and and so
um i'm excited i'm i'm super excited the
process was
very chat if i could talk the process
was very challenging um
i think for all of us um i think one of
the fun parts was
um every dj asked me well what type of
set do you want
right and i i did this on purpose
um i i said
i i want you to play whatever you want
all right you know it's like a golden
ticket you're like it is like
like as a d when you're dj you're like
what do you mean
like but who's the audience right like
and who do i need to please
right with the music and you're like no
do what you want to do
please please yourself it was and it was
cool i think that
um i think every set reflected that 100
percent
because i you know kelly did in the
actual
venue um with people in front of him um
that it's not
100 edm crowd right um originally so
back in september
um he of last year he um
he did a set but it was very i don't
want to use the word safe
but it was definitely
targeted towards the people that he knew
that was going to be there
right you know and mine was it was i'm
going to be honest too it was
safe yeah which is still
fun it is so great it is you know but
and so what you mean by safe
versus whatever you want is like so
if i'm playing jake you have an hour and
just play whatever you want like
sure i'm gonna like the popular lady
gaga song if there's a cool remix of it
like it's like oh cool that's that's
great like i'm gonna love to play that
out
right but i have so many other sweet
songs that nobody has ever heard that i
have like found through crate digging
and
found through like our fun ways of
finding music as a dj
that would it would bump that lady gaga
mix quickly right you know what i mean
so well and i think that you know this
goes into
a previous podcast that we have which
was you know two for you and one for me
two for you one for me and so when you
when you have people in front of you
that you are
you know you're trying to please them
you're trying to maintain
our sales if it's that that type of
environment
right we're not we're not big time
festival djs where
people are there to see you
right and what you do and you know
listen to a set that has 90 of tracks
that
you produced um that's that's just not
the world that
that we are at and so
um it was i think it was
it was fun because i got to tell you
guys to play whatever you want and then
you guys all overthought it
like like everybody everybody i don't
overthink what are you talking about
i i just remember it was i think it was
like four or five days out
you know we're all in our group group
chat and i'm like how how are you guys
sets coming and
and you're like i'm i got a 185 songs
and
i can't peel them narrow down i love
them all
yeah um i'm like how can i play 185
songs in one hour
right how much faster can i mix well
what you do
is you're you produce the event and then
you do two sets
that's i think okay that's what i did
yeah because you so you had so you're
first so
for anybody who's gonna watch it um you
had like a more house set
i did it at the beginning and it was
good it was really good um
and then at the end you have your basics
like more your style which is really
good it was they're both really good i
love them both
it was fun because um you know the cool
thing that that jake did was
i was so i think we're it was about
two two weeks out and i'm
i i think you'll remember the text like
i'm really overwhelmed right now
and because i was not overthinking i was
just over planning
every single aspect and and i'm like
jake i really
you know kelly i need you to take charge
of something
and i need jake i need you to take
charge of something so i don't feel like
i'm just
everything is on me not that it once we
got in the venue it was
all hands on deck feels great but you
know the pre-planning
piece the majority of it up until that
point was
toasty saying you know this is what
we're going to do
and i remember i think we were about
three days out and having that
conversation about you know 185 tracks
and i said i
might you know my my base set was
um my closing set was um it's
pre-planned
you know i picked out specific songs um
i
put them together i ran through it
multiple times
right um it's it's not like it's i'm
hitting play
um but it's i definitely put those
pieces together
and they match in key and the energy
level you know
you've played out that this song goes
well with this song when i transition in
these certain ways like sometimes the
transitions will be different
while you're replaying it live yes but a
lot of times when you're
making a set like this you're going
through and you're like oh my god this
song
oh the word play on this song i'm going
to nail it into the song and then you do
it and
you're like this sounds garbagey right
so you learn yes and no
and in the end when you have what's you
know a pre-planned set isn't
it sounds like i wish there was a better
name for it but right well at least it's
not pre-recorded yeah
not pre-recorded basically you have a
pre your playlist is in the order
that you want to play those songs yes
that's it yep
but you know the house set we were
the opening set i think it was like two
almost two days
we were like right up on the deadline of
what i would feel comfortable of okay
i have a plan set and i'm like i think
i'm gonna cut my my
you know my set even though all the ads
and promotion said toasty you know two
sets that was
that was a thing right and
i just remember jake going i really hope
that you do the second set
like you you should you should do it not
not knowing i mean he didn't know what
was going to be in the set or what it
was just like you should do it
you should do it just like like how can
you
antagonizing me you should do it so
the you know the opening set is it's
freestyled i put that together and i
mean i had
i had songs that i've been listening to
for a couple weeks and like i
really like these but all of it was it
was like
if i was playing a house set for 50
people
dancing it was it was cool it was really
cool
um but the one thing that happened
it was it was really cool
after everybody got off stage
everybody they were it was
exactly like they had just played a set
in front of
two three four five thousand people i'm
serious
everybody as they got off stage were
they were just
walking on clouds and just amped up oh
great
it was it was amazing and it
accomplished i think what
what our number one goal was which is
the creativity aspect
right you know yeah for for me
when it came to planning it because like
like you said i was texting like dude i
haven't even it's like a few days out
and i haven't even like narrowed it down
you know i had a lot of my groupings
done and i'm like okay these couple
songs go together i didn't know how it
was all gonna fit
but i it's funny because you're like
free reign freeway and
for like do what you want to do but and
i'm like okay cool so i've done that
before so like when i started out djing
with these outdoor renegade parties
where we started with
150 people 200 people 300 people we had
up to 500 people at these like very
illegal parties outside uh but they're
awesome and it was literally
it was like like there was some crowd
pleasers for sure like i would
like okay this song's hot right now you
know i'm gonna i'm gonna throw this in
and i'm gonna mix it out
right um we can hear blue bark upstairs
um but
but so it's it's like
i i'm always trying to find songs that
like i don't think anybody's really
heard
right i'm always trying to find remixes
that i don't think anybody's heard i'm
digging deep i'm trying to find them
um but then what actually
helped for me a lot was when you named
it virtual insanity yeah
so it like it clicked for me and then
you showed me the graphic too and i was
like okay so it gave me
it's like i had free reign and then you
helped me narrow it down when you're
like virtual insanity and my brain's
like oh
i can get crazy right yeah you know so
and it like and then when you listen
back i think everybody sets
kind of like flirt with that virtual
insanity
piece of it yeah so no it's cool and
and you know i have we were talking
before we got started
um everybody so there's six sets
you know there's five five groups um
and so when you're editing
you're having to watch through and
there's multiple camera angles and so we
have
um you know we lovingly call it the
booger cam so it's off the front of the
mixer
we have a gimbal which none of us had
operated at gimbal before gimbal is
um a three-way access um
type device that keeps cameras uh smooth
while you're you're moving around and it
helps create some really cool shots um
yeah and then we have um two static
cameras
and so it's um it's
i i know all the sets in inside and out
because i listened to them
two or three times each um as as i was
editing um
and then as i was working the past
couple weeks i've
had them on private soundcloud and and
listened through it multiple times so
um i'm again i'm just excited um
you know it's this weekend it's it's
been a lot of work
coming up to this um but there are
there are some really cool things that i
think are in the works beyond this
um once we get out of kovid um you know
everybody that's been involved like
immediately we're like we need to do
that again
yeah like well hold on let's
let's broadcast the first one and and
then we'll uh you know
maybe we can have some people in front
of us next time that would that would be
pretty awesome but we
we found a new event space that's
another cool thing that's kind of come
out of this
um you know the owners they're like i
think that we could do something here on
a quarterly basis so i
there's some there's definitely some
seeds that have been planted outside you
know outside of the fact that
we put together this super cool thing um
hopefully people are going to watch it
um if you go to glowingthedarkevents.com
you can rsvp for it
and what that will do is um send you to
this the twitch stream
um when it's when it's gonna broadcast
so
um saturday from 7 p.m
until last set starts at midnight so it
is
it's definitely it's going to be a party
so you know grab
grab some beverages and and some disco
lights and
yeah get the big sound system so yeah
that's what i was trying to encourage it
was cool because i had a bunch of homies
telling me and texted me and
you know posting on socials and stuff
and just trying to encourage that like
dude get your closest homies together
get your festival homies together right
like get whoever you would normally like
go to a show with or go
go see see an artist with like get him
over to your house get
10 people five people whatever it is
hook up that sound bar
get the subs knocking get the lights
going get the phillips hues on
right or the go on amazon and order a 12
disco light dump them yeah and it's
it's going to be super cool i mean it is
it's something and if you're listening
to this after it's been premiered which
it should be able to
i think i think yeah i think what will
happen is we'll go to glow in the dark
events.com
and then that'll that will be a jumping
point for hopefully being able to see
them we're going through
honestly we may edit this part out but
we're going through some copyright
challenges
with with youtube um so it's it's an
interesting world
because um you know on twitch you're not
getting pulled twitch
twitch.tv which is a streaming service
if people aren't familiar with that
um normally created or is originally
created for
people that are basically playing video
games
but then it's gone into with covet with
musician
musicians um djs
but you still have copyright broadcast
laws that you're
you're trying to skirt around yeah which
which is like if
if you're unfamiliar with how the
copyright situation goes
it's basically like if i'm playing
i'm a dj but i'm playing a drake song
whether it's a remix or not i'm not
drake
i'm not was it was it universal that he
that he's under who
i am so so that you know basically like
as an artist drake and his people they
want to make sure he's getting paid
every time his songs being played out
and so they have algorithms that detect
the sound they're like oh hey that's a
drake song and it looks like your
youtube account is not drake so
see you later right you clipped well the
cool thing is that i was finding is
and there are some record labels that
their algorithm will find you know
not drake per se but let's say it's a b
level artist
an edm artist right not a mainstream or
not a not a big time
they'll flag the the
stream or the video and say you know
um this is so and so
and rather than pulling the video and
not allowing it to be
broadcast they'll say that's fine you
can do it but you can't monetize it
so anytime that you have you have a um
an ad
that plays during the video that money
would normally go to the
youtuber the person who posted the video
right well instead
they redirect that to the artist
record label which i think is great yeah
that's that's how we should be leaning
really i mean
if they have dude if they have
technology that is able to like filter
every song that's ever played and get
money in the pockets of the person who
produced it like
hell yeah i mean in there i'm going to
as a dj like
find some room for us somehow give me
like
four cents or something i don't know
like give me a cut
but yeah copyright stuff sucks but it's
crazy too because i
i've done a lot of you know we did it
two weekends ago it's been edited for
about a week and so
i've been doing a lot of test uploads
because
gosh forbid i don't want to come in
saturday and
start broadcasting and then having it
yanked 15 minutes in that would be
you know disheartening so it's
interesting you you see the
the youtube algorithm and it picks up
every single song that that i played
that kel's play
that jake played and you're just like
how you know technology-wise
how the heck do you do that that's so
impressive and it's you know and i'm
playing
like heavy edits like with multiple
songs that are in it that are mashed up
and and they're still like oh this is
so-and-so with
with universal and this is so-and-so
with you know capital records and
twitter
it's it's interesting to see it on the
back end so
we're definitely going to we made a
shift to be exclusively on
on twitch um and i'm hoping
that after we get done we'll be able to
rebroadcast it
on twitch so if you can't catch it
saturday don't feel like you're going to
miss out
and we are going to have the sets on
soundcloud
um and that you'll be able to reach that
through glowingthedarkevents.com too
i think they'll just be a nice jump off
point have you been pinged on soundcloud
at all
no that's so have they been chill lately
but they have been
i've had fist fights with stupid
soundcloud yeah
i dude i have i have i have
uh probably eight or nine mixes you know
and they're some of them are very
mainstream clubby and some of them are
very
um you know dubstep trap and um i've had
any of them yanked
now i don't have you know thousands of
followers either so
i don't know if that plays into you know
i i've gone through multiple
like through my what eight nine years of
djing i've gone through
multiple soundcloud accounts and it's
like so discouraging
when you're sounding crowded account
gets deleted right dude when my first
one got deleted i don't know how many
followers i had but
it was a good amount and then you like
think that like okay well my followers
will re-follow the next one and like you
don't even get
150th of your followers
yeah so but i mean although they do have
other places like mix cloud i have a lot
of my old catalog
from mixes is up on mexicolad um so
that's good we're gonna be able to
listen back to him on soundcloud there's
still a lot of people that use
soundcloud
yeah i can jam those out and those are
good for
running at the gym they're good for
parties i like it good for anything
um so yeah man
i feel like we covered that pretty well
i'm
very excited to do it i think that yeah
you slide that on over to me
it went really well like the energy in
the room like saturday night i wish that
someone had just taken one like there
was one extra person in the room who
just walked around and watched we were
like a band
like like whoever's on lights like like
i was just
jamming on lights and then and then
melissa's next to me just killing it on
the laser
you're you're djing kelly's on gimbal
it's like
all kind of new stuff for us in a way oh
yeah
it's and it's amazing that like we
didn't have a major
catastrophic something happen yeah
that's true
like like i mean we you know i had all
the artists in front of us
i'm on saturday i gave you know a big
thank you for coming type speech and and
all of that
we're gonna we're gonna do a pause real
quick we'll edit this out okay
oh you're gonna oh oh i was like
no no i've literally taken bong rips on
my podcast nice
i mean so you know we're sitting in
front of everybody and i'm giving the
big you know
it's the big game speech and i said
if you mess up if you mess up it 55
minutes into your set
i don't want you to worry about it we'll
stop and we'll redo it
right and so and and i was serious i
mean we had enough slack in the in the
timeline and because i wanted everybody
to
look good and sound good right and um
like i said you know we start out you
know with with talking about
their the the mixes are live and there's
there's spots that you know as
perfectionists were like oh i wish that
was
just a little bit tighter you know but
um they're all great sets and and we
didn't have anything fail
i mean we didn't have like cameras crash
on us
or lights that look bad or lasers that
we're going out yeah i mean it was it
was great
and so it was very rewarding
like i said we got off stage and of
course we had we had kelly's huge
mains that you know we had angled we
were
that were angled up as as monitors i
mean we look like zomboy up there with
you know
with the huge old um they're called def
drummer is the normal monitoring term
but um it was
it was cool it was it was really cool
and it was an amazing experience um
you know i talked about um
magical and and you know i'm sure people
see my posts online and like what is
this guy on
you know it's it was
it was extremely humbling um to have
multiple
people involved that didn't get
i mean they didn't get they get paid
they did not get paid
um and there was no expectation to get
paid
um and the whole creative process was
was really cool um you know we didn't
you'll see in in the video there was
these really neat led lights that that
we'd never used before
and so jake and i had to kind of figure
out okay where are we going to put them
how are we going to use them what are
they going to look like and they look
phenomenal on film
it's like and we we could have really
just screwed up like put them in the
wrong spot and just had
horrible footage i mean just all the
stars aligned
um for it and there's you know there's
new friendships
friendships that came out of it um like
for real dude those guys are so dope
yeah
yeah and they want to come back already
like like i've been
i you know of course i'm excited about
it so i've been
showing them little teasers and and i
and we were doing some test streaming
last weekend and
kelly and i were texting and all sudden
these
other person jumps into the stream that
you know it's a private account i'm like
what the heck who are these guys and
it's like oh it's for real oh man we
can't wait to this looks awesome you
know and they're all excited
so i'm excited to to to definitely do it
again
um i think that and and everybody that
was involved
definitely wants to do it again and i
think that hopefully people
when they watch it this weekend they're
like i i want to go
see that right in person yeah you know
definitely and i think and i think that
that's
you know that's the next step once we
get through this this culvert craziness
yeah i think that i mean i'm sure that
anybody listening
if even if they don't consider
themselves like a creator or like an
artist
or or any of those things that like we
call ourselves or we try to be or
whatever
i think that they probably know somebody
and they probably know somebody who's
like
you know that that dude or that girl
if they're not able to create once in a
while they go crazy like it's it's
it's this outlet of like it's also it's
this thing that you love to do
like djing for example like i love to dj
but there's also
like if i'm not djing or or creating
something
i feel like i'm not fulfilling myself i
feel like i'm going stir crazy i feel
like i'm just like dude i
gotta get this idea out of here and i
got like because at all times my brain
is just populating cool brilliant ideas
and when you're just stuck at home and
you're not able to do any events so
you're not able to do any of the things
that you've
practiced doing and being a professional
at right
like you go a little crazy so it's dude
i was super grateful to be able to just
creatively do something you know and
it's in i felt like
like i i started my dj journey like i
said like with those renegade parties
uh you know as as my alias dj kronos and
and i feel like man i felt so fulfilled
doing those types of sets because
i was like man this is you know it's
this is i can mix these songs and i can
put together specific songs in certain
ways
that nobody in the in in the world is
gonna do like but me
and it's just this very it's really fun
because there's
you know djing for
a crowd like you're getting paid at a
club or a bar to dj
yeah it's super fun and you could
definitely make it your own you could
definitely make it creative
but there's only so many like edits or
like playing with the songs that you can
do for people like bro just play the
song
you know like the people just you know
and you got to follow the trends
you got to play what's what's popular
right now you've got to do the correct
throwbacks at the correct
time of the night uh it's it's very
complicated
yeah but it's it's exhausting too so i
like to compare it to like um
uh and i've probably used this analogy
on the on the podcast i don't even know
if it's an analogy
similarly but uh essentially like you're
not going to
when you're like okay we need someone to
play acoustic guitar at our wedding
oh we know steve and he's the lead
singer of the metal band he'll
love to do it because it's a guitar and
it's the same exact thing
right you hit up steve and he's like
dude i don't want to play acoustic
guitar at your wedding i don't even play
cozy guitar what are you talking about
right
like it's they're very different things
they're actually had this recently
um my mom i mean
lover of pieces she had a friend
that um younger she's getting married
and they they they knew who i was
um and oh we want brian to dj our
wedding
i mean you don't it it's not going to be
enjoyable for me
you know and and i'm not going to do a
good job
honestly i mean let's let's i mean let's
maybe phrase it
in an appropriate way i'm not a wedding
dj anymore i used to be a wedding dj
you know wedding djs are great at what
they do yeah like
i mean i've dj'd weddings it's a whole
different side of me that you have to
really like prepare
like but and it's really important i
mean because you are
it's you know quote it's very cliche but
the most important day of of you know
the pride
groom's lives yeah i do not really but
but i mean that's
that's the mindset and you know to have
that pressure of
not wanting to screw up i mean as
pleasers we as djs we're all pleasers
right i mean we definitely want we're
there to
please ourselves as well as that sounds
but we're definitely there to fulfill
something within us
but we're definitely there to please the
crowd
right otherwise we wouldn't be doing it
well if you look at a dj
if you're ever at any club or bar you'll
notice that every song they play they're
taking a glance around
every single song they play they're
assessing the room okay make sure
they're tapping their foot
people aren't tapping their foot oh okay
i went a little too hard into the trap
genre it seems like maybe i'll let off
on that gas pedal
right um i'm just when you have the
freedom to create something artistically
it's just so
freeing you know i mean it's and it's
when you're djing a wedding
i just you know you're going to play
kenny logan's footloose right and it's
michael jackson
yeah yeah exactly experiences
but yeah so so it's great and it's it's
it's also a story i feel like a lot of
the times if you list like so
definitely with like my set definitely
with kelly's like if you listen to any
of his brain hack series
like you you definitely tell this is
like right up in that line this is like
a
kell set and for me it was like i'm
definitely someone who i'm like if i
have someone's attention how can i tell
them a story
like how can i have kind of reoccurring
themes that like you only kind of get if
you're listening intently you know
and i i i'm pretty sure that the three
of you guys have
the same sort of thing it's like telling
a short little story like here's what
i'm trying to communicate you
to you in this next hour but also you
can dance your face off during
sure sure well and it's you know for me
it's um it's definitely energy flow
you know so um i like to
raise and lower the energy level in a
room
you know and um especially when i'm when
i'm doing
uh clubs gigs you know i don't like i
said i
i'm trying to create my own party at
this point
so i've moved moved on from um
i think doing you know club gigs for
somebody else meaning
top 40 hip-hop type based clubs but
one thing that i that i that i know
personally and that
that i've with talking with guests at
these places
is people and i'm proud to say this
people know
uh a toasty set people know
okay toasty's here right and that's
that's not being braggy it's just
how i present myself and how i present
the music
and you know it's what type of remix and
and
and what you know when i play the remix
and what type of energy level i'm trying
to achieve at a certain point in the
night
so um
as an artist you know if you're if
you're a live
performer you know if you're playing an
instrument you want people
when they walk into a room not even
looking up on stage or looking over into
the corner and say
oh that's so-and-so i i know who that is
right and get a good feeling about it
obviously but but
you know a warmth and like oh that's you
know
and that's that's what i've i've i've
tried to do over my
you know at least my club side not
obviously weddings you know
but um on the club side of things people
walk in and like
all right we're here so i can tell
toasty's here
you know and it's going to be a party
dude i always love that i always love
when uh like i'm playing at like the
local bar and telling playing silverstar
or something
and i'm up in the corner and then like
i'll have a homie just like
you can i can see them coming up to me
and they've been there for a while right
they're like bro i didn't even realize
this was you up here until i like
listened to like like they're just
hanging out they just you know there's
some dj of course
but then after you know after a half
hour they're like
this guy's you know play the songs i
like or whatever it is you know
it's it's cool because djs are able to
kind of
you know we're playing other people's
music right but
you're still able to create your own
style yep that's just so freaking cool
well
it's like when you're digging for music
like you know the way that you dig for
music and the songs that you pick out
are 100 different
than what i pick out you know i i will
you know
at least in you know you people will
hopefully be able to see in the
in the sets on this weekend that you
know all the
i there are some remixes in there
there's some remixes of some popular
songs there's
you have remixes of popular songs right
that um that
it was um it was prince was
it was erotic city right uh 1999
oh it was uh it was prince but it was
a girl well what's that why am i spacing
it
so good we'll edit it in later but
that's not something that i would play
i love it i absolutely love the track i
love the remix right i love prince
but i love the remix that he played but
it's not it's not toasty
you're right you know what i mean and so
um but there's stuff that's that's in
mine
it's like you listen to it you're like
you
you could dig it right but as as a dj
you're like
yeah that's cool and i can see where
people just lose their minds but that's
not me
right so it's it's as a dj we're not
we're definitely playing other people's
music but you know there's definitely a
flare
or a seasoning if you want to think of
it that way that yeah that people are
trying to do seasoning is perfect
because we talk about taste
i mean there's i you know you can
for me i feel like and i think we may
have talked about this on that last one
too but it's just it's
it's basically like transitions timing
taste yeah like those are kind of like
you're kind of three like as a dj like i
mean because you could be playing
the hottest songs but if you're playing
them at
10 p.m and the club doesn't get there
till 11 30
right you know like you gotta time it
all and then your
your own taste like even when you're
playing for a crowd that you're being
paid for
you uh or like a you know at like where
you need to play what's popular right
now
right you're still going to have some
taste you're not just going to go
exactly on the spotify top and be like
okay i'm going to make sure i play all
20 of these songs
you know you're going to you're going to
filter in your own taste and you're
going
to well you can you can but then you're
just a jukebox
yeah and djs are not a jukebox and and
and honestly djs that do that they're
just like oh i'm gonna i'm gonna play
off the hot 100. that's it
that's it right it's boring there's not
an
i mean they're playing all the hits i
mean hey there is there is a
there's room for him you know it's
i don't know how i feel about that but i
don't think there is i mean i think
about it like if i walk into pop-out
yeah if i walk into a venue and it's
like and i see i've seen
you know in my music director experience
i've worked with a lot of young djs i've
mentored a lot of djs
you know that's what they want to do you
know like oh i want to be a hip-hop dj
and i want to play all of the you know
the bangers
that's all i'm going to play like
because i'm a hip-hop head i'm like well
one
there's a lot of hip-hop out there right
there's
um 80s hip-hop there's you know 90s
there's golden arrow
2000s there's backpack hip-hop there's
i mean there there's so many you know
there's west coast there's east coast
there's now too there's a weird like
bedroom hip-hop there's
you know south south hip-hop southern
hip-hop i mean there there's so many
there's so much hip-hop out there just
like there's so much edm
so much house i mean so you know to say
that oh you're gonna
you know be the the jammin
107.5 you know hip-hop dj and you're
going to play just those cuts right
you're limiting yourself one and two
you're it's kind of boring
like i'm gonna you know because if you
think about it like
where hip-hop music is right now if
you're gonna play like
the hot 10 like half the night's gonna
be drake
i know right and so sometimes sometimes
like if i look back at my set i'm like i
just played so much drake tonight which
is
you know sometimes it works i like drake
it used to be you know rihanna for me a
couple years ago it's like
there's so many songs that i play you
know chris brown you're like so many
songs and like
that you could play besides that but
it's
you just i have no clue where we're
going with that but
just just cornering ourselves i was
going to ask do you think that
when you first started djing how was
your taste
horrible was it like what was it only
were you trying to play only songs that
you liked or what
what do you think you are because i
think for me when i started going into
it so
i got into djing because i discovered
electronic music and i'm like
holy mother of like nobody around
me like
i love it i want to share with you
everybody to me i was like bro
nobody in my hometown i mean there's
probably plenty of people i just didn't
know him but i was like
my hometown has ever listened to any of
this and like first thing i went once i
went i went to rusco as my first show
yeah
and then i immediately like the next day
and i was probably just super hungover
but the next day i was like
hit up all my homies i'm like dude
there's this she's crazy
you have no idea what's going on um and
actually the the shirt that i wore the
wake the up shirt yeah for uh
uh glow in the dark was i purchased that
at my first rescue show really yeah
so um so it's vintage it's a vintage
shirt but uh so i
i was basically like i was you know i'd
send it all my friends and they were
like what this is crazy and then i
discover
another one my friends had just found
like skrillex right you know and that
was like the heat of it but
i you know for me my taste was i was
like i just like dude you guys have to
listen to stuff it makes you
feel just another like this electronic i
think i think i just called everything
house or dubstep back then it was if it
wasn't house it was dubstep
right and there was the first three
years where everybody thought everything
i played was dubstep right
i i think i i got hired for events and
they would call them
like dubstep party and i'm like wouldn't
play any dubstep it would be like
just a mix of all electronic but right
but the the taste was really formed from
like as i started listening to any music
like once you decide to be a dj and that
you're going to show it to people
anything i listen to i'm like is this
something that i want to show other
people is this something that i think
that
perhaps many people haven't heard or
it's it's something that's
because it changes over like over the
course you start like okay oh i have
this song that will go with this song
and then i'm trying to get this sort of
vibe but at the beginning it was all
just like i would hear songs
play it yeah they probably didn't go
together at all but right
oh my gosh so you know i got
i was djing in in high school um i
started doing that
um because i couldn't dance and i was
kind of a nerd and
um you know i classically trained piano
and
bassoon and trombone and all that right
and just kind of a music nerd
um and
i wanted to be involved with social
stuff
but i really was socially awkward and so
i got into djing and so
i was working with a guy locally scott
nettling with music more djs great guy
and i said i you know i need to rent
some speakers
for for this high school dance that i'm
doing at
my high school and uh he uh
he said well once just you know if he
needs speakers once you take like my
whole setup so like
all of his music and all that right and
i didn't have i'm not 16. i didn't have
a huge music
collection when that was back that was
that even before the limewear
no yeah there was there was no pirating
going on it was it was all you had to
purchase like sam goody and
and sam goody all of the you know all of
the
uh columbia house so you do a
subscription for like 14 free cds for a
penny
all that jazz right so yeah so i got
into it and
and started doing high school dances and
then he's
he's like hey you know i know that you
know how to use the equipment i need to
do a wedding
i'm like all right cool right so i
started doing that
and um you know i grew up listening to
60s 70s and 80s music because my folks
their age and that kind of stuff and
and um really didn't
so it was about 2 000
[Music]
about 2 000. um i just moved back from
arizona um from a failed college career
um and i was in a venue
and they were playing this is in 2000
in callouts county um they're playing
house music
and nobody nobody liked it
everybody hated it um they're like
what is this stuff and so the owners
they were they were pretty progressive i
mean they're
they wanted to own a nightclub and and
they wanted to have um
you know house djs and that was their
thing
and who the dj was um um
it was jeff and micah and i can't
remember their dj names
and i'm gonna tag them in the podcast
when it when it posts but
it was hilarious because um i thought
that they were garbage because
i didn't like electronic music right and
they weren't and they weren't keeping
anybody there
i'm gonna let you know that those two
cats were
really good house djs and i feel bad
that i didn't realize it at the time um
because
i'm in there and i'm you know punk
punk ass 22 year old and
i've had a couple of red bull vodkas and
i'm
talking up the owners and i'm like yeah
we need a top 40 dj in here if you guys
want to like make any money
and it was like the next weekend i
auditioned and
did a top 40 set and people stuck around
and they made money and those two guys
didn't didn't get booked anymore
so it was i just booted them because i
played garbage top 40
and they wouldn't they you know they
they they were playing what the owners
wanted the owners
wanted to have a progressive
house based club this was in longview
back in 2000 this was before
the edm boom before all of it right
that's just i mean dude you need an
audience
and they were playing vinyl you know and
that's even more epic
yeah it was great and i had no clue how
to beat match like i was just doing the
the wedding reception fade in fade out
um
you know i reflect back now and i feel i
mean i'm friends with them
um on facebook and we chat hopefully
jeff's gonna watch this weekend i don't
know
mike after hearing that but uh
he lost me a job yeah yeah um
but you know there's and they're both
still in the scene and they're you know
they
um they they do events they've been
doing streaming events you know they
they're definitely house heads and so um
so at first i you know i was just
playing garbage music i was just playing
whatever
kept people there to drink and then
allowed me to drink
um on top of it heavily um which is
where dj toasty uh came from
so because my first night um
well hold on it was it was the night
before i
um auditioned and i was in there
and just got blasted you know i'm 21 i'm
a punk kid
um can't handle my liquor and
um bounce off every single wall as i'm
walking out
and so the next night i walk in and you
know i'm hungover and
i'm like all right let's do my you know
audition
and they're like well what's your dj
name and it was something stupid i think
it was like
i i i'm gonna sheepishly admit this i
think it was like dj blaze it up
stop yeah it was it was bad
it was super bad right and i don't even
smoke weed but i bet you if you looked
it up right now there'd be like seven
thousand dj right just on fire right
so i so i told him i'm like yeah i think
it's you know dj blaze it up
and they're like no no you're
you're toasty right and so this was
the this is 2000 so you know 20 years
ago
and so i just started getting into it
well then
then they brought a hip-hop dj up from
portland and he was really uh popular
his name was
dj kryptic um and
steve and he was a great vinyl dj great
great and um so i kind of got pushed
aside
and but i still wanted to play right and
so i
started really getting in the house
jokingly
i mean as i pushed the other house djs
out and then i started going to shows in
in portland went to a couple of raves
um changed my perspective on music
um this will change your perspective on
life yeah that's true
there's nothing like walking out of an
underground rave i'm in
uh southeast portland at 5 30 in the
morning and the sun's out
and i'm just gonna tell you that that it
was you know
it was definitely um life-changing
yeah it was life-changing and there you
know so
i i started really getting into um house
music
and um i would open up the night and
then
cryptic would uh do the hip-hop and keep
the people there drinking right and then
it i mean at the time i didn't realize
this but it was smart by the owners
about 1 30 i would do my closing set of
house music right and it was horrible i
couldn't beat match
um i i was a very crappy dj back in 2000
so
just being a little humble here um but
it would start people
you know people that were in house music
they're like yeah this is kind of cool
and the other people that weren't
they'd close their tabs out and go home
right so it's
in the industry it's called a soft close
yeah yeah hard closes
people up yeah hard closes you go right
up to 2 a.m you know you're going hard
and you just flip on the lights and tell
people to get the f out right
so soft closes you start about 1 30 and
either start playing graphic music
apparently that was house and me um or
um you start playing
softer music and you bring the lights up
slowly and then they push out but
so it's just it was kind of how my role
was um
but um i think that
um it gave me an opportunity to you know
share music that i liked uh with people
um and you know i go to a show on friday
night and come back and think that i was
at that time it was you know bad boy
bill and richard vision and you know all
those
dj irene um all those fast mixing um
type you know early 90s late 2000s djs
so i'd come back and
try to do that in lawn view which it did
not work at all
you know hungover from the night before
still so
um but i think that gets into um
you know some of the um the other things
that that we wanted to talk about
yeah i think with i mean we did want to
cover
i mean dude we look we work in the music
industry
like mental health for
any person who's creative for any person
who's
artistic for any person who drinks or
smokes or does any sort of drugs
uh i mean like so so did you
i mean were you just doing like the
typical
like you you were just partying at that
time because i mean because i was
partying a ton all the time too like i
mean
i was i was doing a ton of the same
yes um
and it's funny because it may be funny
isn't the best word but
like looking back it's kind of weird
because
in the moment you're like dude i'm
living my life i love my it's so great
everything's going good and then when
you retrospectively sometimes when
you're like doing a little better or
you're doing just elsewhere in your life
you retrospectively
glance back and you're like man i was
kind of a show for a little bit
there wasn't i like i was kind of like
hiding from some stuff i didn't even
know i was hiding from you know i was i
mean it wasn't
i would even use the word um beyond
show i was i was a piece of
yeah i mean really it was um
you know you bring up self-reflection
and
you know i've been doing this 25 years
um i have
i i won't say quote real job i have a a
full-time job that pays for the house
and
and the kids and you know the wife of 15
years and and
you know allows me to be uh stable
um but i look back
and i just can't believe that
that was the person that that i used to
be
and you know i remember i remember
i mean there was there was so much
partying going on
so much and you get wrapped up in that
that everything revolves around you
that you know there's the the club that
i was spinning at had a capacity of
about
250 people you know we were the hot spot
in town so
we were packed all the time at that
point you know i'm reflecting back now
it didn't matter really what we played
or how we played it
we were just the spot right and so we
could i i was getting away with
crummy mixing bad transitions you know
yeah and and it didn't matter um
and then i was you know part of the
party
um you know i would start the night out
with three other entertainment guys
there and we start out with
around a jaeger and the jaeger didn't
stop all night
and you know then there was um
mixed drinks and um you know it was
it was not it wasn't good um because
the the problem that that i had back
then
you know and and i've matured and and
and a little bit um
and have established boundaries and and
understanding self-understanding of you
know who i am and
and what what i need to do um
i was just lost i was lost i was so much
into
the party um there was one crazy night i
i um i actually invited my mom
she came down and she had some
co-workers with her some girlfriends
and you know she was up in the vip area
and
and i came by and
part of my pay there was half trade
and half cash and so you know i was
there would be sometimes that that my
paycheck would actually be negative
like i would have drank more than the
trade and
what they owed me but i came up to my
mom and i'm like you know here try this
like here try this and so like at 1 30
in the morning like
the party's rocking and she kind of
stops me and she says you realize that
you've come by 14 times
and i said yeah she goes and those were
all your drinks
i got yeah she goes so you've had 14
drinks
either christ were you in your djing
yeah
yeah how do you think your transitions
were oh i'm sure i'm sure there were
what if there's a recording that you
were forced to listen to so
it's funny you bring that up i actually
found we were cleaning out the basement
and i found an old cd um so that dates
me
a cd case and it has a dj
toasty uh winter mix 2004
and it is hot garbage it
is it is horrible it is horrible but at
the time i thought it was great
i just i thought it was great um so yeah
she uh
she kind of called me out she goes you
know you've had 14 drinks tonight and
i'm like yeah
and you know all these people are having
a good time and it's i mean i was
arrogant about it
it was bad like i'm winning mom don't
you see right everybody's having a good
time and this is you know my
every time a good time because of me
and you know that that went on for
a couple years and um
i will i will let the audience speculate
on how i could have had 14 drinks and
still been sober
so um you know you
you want to keep the party going and you
know when you get up to
a normal human gets up to about four or
five drinks and you can't keep the party
going
so there was a lot of that and
um i'm gonna tell you that you know i i
was not
a good human being it was it was
um you know i look back now and um
it's it's not something to be proud
about um i know that we're jokingly
talking about it but um
you know that you just get so wrapped up
in
you know i'm a dj and and i'm
throwing the party so i have to be part
of the party
and i remember sitting on
the front porch of
[Music]
my wife and i's apartment at the time
and um i'm loaded
you know i i think at the time i
probably drove home um
you know just bad bad decisions up and
down
and you know she just looks at me and
she and she
she at first wanted to be part of the
party she thought it was cool right she
moved up and
everything's cool and then she realized
that
i had a lot of problems because of
all the partying so we're sitting on the
porch and of course i'm in
a inebriated state you know and she goes
um
i'm i'm going to leave unless you do
something different
so at that time i think it had been like
four
or five years of just djing and partying
solid
and that's that's what my identity was
was that i was a dj and i was going to
be
a dj and um
you know i just cried um i cried like a
little baby
um because you know i
snot nosed in her shoulder or i'm like i
don't know what i'm going to do
you know i'm just a dj you know what
else can i do
yeah what else my eggs in this basket
right that's all i'm good for
whatever yeah that's that's all my worth
is that
i am just a dj and
but it was it was it was tough because
there are so many things that came out
of that time period
um minus the the fact that i had a
substance abuse problem and minus that i
was an alcoholic right
there were so many skill sets that i
learned from being
a dj and you know event programming
or event planning and
customer service and budgeting
and event promotion and
marketing you know all those pieces that
i wasn't just a dj
i was doing all these other things as
well um
but i was just a dj that liked to party
and if i could have removed that
which which i ended up doing um then it
allowed me to
to grow into the other pieces that i had
taken
and so fortunately you know she didn't
leave
and fortunately um i had an opportunity
to change careers
um and take a break from from that
aspect
i mean i and i still had um i
i i still um had
um drinking and subs abuse problems
during that transition too um so it's
it wasn't like it i just stopped djing
and then it then all that
all those challenges went away um so
it was uh it was nice to have obviously
someone
um you know obviously my family and and
and others be able to support
that decision that you know i couldn't
be in that environment
because it just it was toxic it was
it was fun i was having a good time but
um it was it was not good yeah
i mean but when it's dude it's like when
it's always available
when it's all especially when it's like
half your pay
it's like like all you got to do is
i mean we're we're creatures of habit
that's for sure
so that's a part of it but it's also
kind of like environment plays a huge
role
in our actions oh yeah you know like and
that's not to blame anything on our
environments
for sure but a lot of our like our
sternness of like
i don't want to you know it's it's
monday or tuesday and you're like dude
this weekend i'm going to stay away from
that
right or this weekend i'm only going to
have two beers before i play or whatever
it is
but when you're there and then you know
people are bringing you shots or
someone's got
got got the goods whatever it is it's
too easy to
give in in that moment and kind of
forget like
what your long-term goals of who you are
well and
any of those substances are obviously
used to be able to escape what
you know you need to be working on um
i i always dread you know being
hungover because then the next day
you're you're a slug
and you you lose that day
you you lose i mean depending on how how
hard you go
um you might lose 24 hours meaning not
productive at all
right yeah so if
if you know if you're losing 12 hours of
life and you know one
one thing that that as i have gotten
older
um when at least for me when i was
younger
i didn't i'm seemed to
just not exist like
you know party every weekend
um no no there was
there was time did not seem like it was
fine like it was going to end
and as you get older
time seems to speed up
so you know i'm 41 now
and you know you have parents around you
that are older you have kids
you know that you have a daughter that's
starting seventh grade and you have a
son that's in fifth grade and it just
felt like yesterday that
you know they had water wings and
they're in the pool um
so one thing that that
helps me now at least which
i don't know it's kind of weird is the
the fact that i'm aware
of time like time is super important to
me
um whether or not it's um
creative active create creative
activities that i put my
my time and effort into whether or not
it's helping people out
as crummy as that sounds um
you know work um if
something is taking up my time it has to
be worth something
to me and it doesn't have to be monetary
you know like the the glow
glow-in-the-dark
uh obviously was not monetary you know
we spent
um quite a bit of money on it um
i'm not going to get anything
back from that cash wise right let's
let's define that very clearly right
but i am going to get an immense amount
of
friendship out of it uh art our artistic
creativity um future opportunities with
other creative
endeavors so that's something that you
know i'll sink my time into
um people hitting me up and asking me if
i can fix their computer
you know that's my time is worth a
certain amount of money
and so you know we i need to make sure
that
that i'm getting paid
for those types of things but um
i i think that i i like to remind myself
and something that you know
it like took me a while to figure out
myself but
money is not the only currency not you
know in
in i think as an individual it's up to
you to choose
what what are currency what's a currency
to you what are you spending what what's
what's in your wallet right right like
because we each have different things
like you know at the beginning
conversation we're talking about how
like i'm not only i feel less crazy when
i'm able to do something artistic but
it's also it's something that
fills me up it's like like when i'm done
do it like like after i'm done with my
set i'm like cool like
like do you know it's not like okay i'm
ready to die right now like i'm
fulfilled i'm so happy like i'm just
enlightened whatever
it's just like you're gonna
come to a point in your life when you're
like what did i care about what did i
spend my time doing what did i
did i really fill up what i wanted to do
and i think that
a lot of us never have a chance to or we
never stop
enough to see time and be like
what do i want what do i want out of
this right and it's too easy to kind of
take the
take the treats take they're like hey
why don't you just drink one
like it could be fun just this weekend
sure um
yeah it it it builds up i think that uh
thanks for sharing all that too by the
way man this is super great i
for me um
it's it's it's hard to quantify i mean i
i think once i have a little more
distance
from because i definitely had my times
of where
it'd be a few years of like when we're
doing those outdoor parties
like the like driving after drinking at
the end of the night
substances at the end of the night um
not wanting the party to end
and these things started to add up for
me like after a couple years for me it
would be like
that hangover the next day would turn
into depression that i didn't know was
depression i was like i thought that i
was my thoughts i thought that i was
deserved everything that i thought about
myself like all these things
um and
we get caught in our own identities
don't we
like it's so weird like we're like like
like you've probably experienced you
know like when
especially when it's your hometown and
it's this small small town
situation people are chanting your name
your dj name right like
that's like this weird unhealthy thing
it is like in in it and it fuels
everything that you do
so if they're they're chanting kronos
and i'm like what does chronos mean to
them
well i got i better make sure i'm
representing that i better make sure i'm
going him i better make sure i'm doing
this like
and then um and then for me i started
dealing with like on top of the
depression i started dealing with
social anxiety like while i'm on stage
and so you know a couple more beers
feels good right or
or a little line feels good gets you to
get you to zone in
you know i when i was when i was in
portland i was you know working for
um a big restaurant group down there
the i remember
i remember the the first
set that i did for for the club and this
this club was
top 10 um nightclubs in united states
back in
um between 2005 and 2006.
and so i mean it's it wasn't a mega club
but its capacity was i think like 800
and we'd we'd pack in like 1100 people
right and and my first set was
um ufc had played at
the it was rose rose quarter at that
point wasn't modem
i'd have been modem we had the quote
official
and it was official after our or after
party
for usc when they performed or when they
fought
i don't i guess they don't perform when
they fight
uh in portland right there's 1100 people
in the building
1100 people and it was the most people
that i'd ever dj'd for
right and i just stepped up and i did a
set
um and it was it was all right it was
good i mean but
i played the right songs at the right
times and and that and that
energy level right so
we did we had that night and um
the owners you know the there was an
issue with the existing
music director and he went on vacation
he didn't come back from vacation
so yeah so you know you talk about
um arrogance
like you know i do that set and then
they get rid of that guy
and for whatever reason and then i
i try to remember i think it was three
or four months later
i kind of had to prove my worth right
and so then i was the music director and
i'm going to tell you that
there was a lot of a lot of arrogance
a lot of arrogance and i was drinking
[Music]
and i just wasn't a nice person i wasn't
a good human
it was you know i had this facade um
that i wanted to help people out and i
wanted to you know help them be
successful and you know
teaching younger djs how to dj but
it was it was all look at me
my most important you know i wanted to
establish my name
you know i had all these grandiose ideas
that i was gonna become a touring dj and
all this other stuff right
and a lot of that was was fueled from
the fact that i was
drinking you know and
i was making good money but we never had
any money
you know um so that tells you anything
it's
it's it's
again it's interesting you know you get
in those situations where
you feel that you are important
right and you're important because of
quote maybe who you are
or what you do or how you do it and at
the end of the day
um i wasn't important i mean i i mean
as a human i'm important of course but
in that situation i was just another
dj i was just another music director
right and
you can work hard at your job and do
your job well
um but god if you're a prick to people
does it really matter you know i was
making okay money
meaning above average money and i was
the center of attention
and i was helping running the music
department for
you know multiple um calm stores but
multiple bars you know you look back
you're like does it does that really
matter would it have been better if i
would have been
better to other people and not drinking
as much
and you know home more often
and watch my kids grow
you know as infants more rather than
just working all the time
and you know it plays into um
you know your mental health and how you
know your stability
and i think you know when when you are
so wrapped up in what you're doing
and using
heavily whether or not that's legal
substances really or illegal substances
and you lose focus of what
is important like you're focusing on the
wrong things
and instead of
you know you know to basically pull your
head up and look around
and take a deep breath and and see what
is important um and i think that
substance abuse and and you know
drinking too much whether or not it's
abuse or addiction
um and that's a fine fine line for
people
um it's it's not
it's not good and
you know the nice thing for me is that i
that i have
made it through those different stages
in my life
um and the nice thing is that i can
reflect back and say you know i
i don't ever want to be that person
again
that's that's i mean besides
the different skills and and experiences
that that you get from different stages
in your life
um i can self-reflect and think
that like i said looking back i don't
ever want to be that person again
right you know i don't want to ever be
um that
toasty again dj toasty yeah um
because there's definitely
you know i think that if you talk to
different people in
in different stages in my life you know
as an artist as a dj as a human
um i'm very much a different person
in each one each one of those stages and
i don't know i think that it helps you
become stronger um
with growing from
those opportunities you know i have the
one opportunity which was
um on the on the porch at the apartment
you know and i need to do something
different because
this isn't working um and
i at the time realized that you know
all i am as a dj which wasn't true i
wasn't just a dj
um that was a moment um i think that
um when the company that i was working
for
at the time closed that nightclub
because it wasn't doing as well
um and then my identity was gone
and they you know they came to me and
said hey we're gonna keep you on but
we're gonna have to reduce your pay
because well we don't have this
big nightclub right um it made me
rethink a lot of things
like okay well if i'm
i need to go do something different and
so
you know those are all chapters in our
lives and and it's it's helped me
try to remember what is important and
like i said looking back at you know
that story of
walking up with 14 drinks to my mom i i
would
i would never ever ever do that again
ever you know yeah i mean it's it's
crazy because that really is just like
uh
like you said you know if you talk to
different people at different times your
life they'd have a you know different
opinion of you they've met a different
side of you
you know but the the truth of life is
those those have all been you
you know those have all been that's true
like
those have all been like part of your
journey but like the fact that you're
you're willing and able to intelligently
like at this point in your life you come
on a podcast and talk about it sure you
know because you know that it's going to
be beneficial to other people well i
mean think of your nice relationship
yeah like you and i first met it was at
the casino right and you were
the guy right and i'm nobody
and i'm coming in and i'm basically you
know buffing my chest out and you're
like who's this guy right
and like you're first interaction
is definitely not what we have now
and what i remember about you at that
point in time
is totally different from what you and i
have right now
so i was being strangled by my ego i
don't even know what it was right
yeah i mean well and that's the thing so
so so for me i've had
because it's hard because i think once
you get more retrospect once you get a
little more distance you can look
back and be like dude these are the
definitive moments where it was like you
got to get your together you got to
do this like for me
i had a few years back where i was doing
too much blow
yeah and i had a time where
it was this weird thing and i've talked
about it on here before and i
basically so i've never been someone who
like i never got like
trashed like i've never been like
like i was usually able to like say no
to to the shots
or uh you know i i wasn't everybody like
i would never get like super
up but also you know there's the
other things that involved that keep you
not super up right of course but
so
i for for my definitive moment was
shaylee and i were i wasn't even working
i was just out at a bar
um we were just hanging out we're having
a good time and and
it was just like people's birthday i
randomly i didn't plan on it but people
bought me more shots than i planned on
drinking that night right
i go to get behind the wheel and i'm
driving chilly and i i had blow
so i pulled out my pocket and i did a
bump before i drove to you know so i can
drive better right and like i did it and
i was like
i have this clarity of like what the
have i made normal
what am i i'm just looking at this
wonderful person next to me i'm just
like
what if i just made norm like she didn't
bad nigh because it was something like
didn't do it all the time but she was
like okay i get it i guess you know
right
like what have i made normal to this
person and
so i think something important that we
could dig a little more into
is how do we
how do we speak to i mean i know it's
coded right now there's nobody who's
djing and doing bumps before the bar
right now but like
how do we because because what the ego
does is it keeps your identity exactly
what it is because it's safe and it's
good and people are changing your name
so why would you change
and and it'll protect you and it'll keep
you in these same habits
and it'll it'll make you miss these
wonderful beautiful life opportunities
of that light bulb of like what are you
doing you knucklehead right like or you
know like
are you gonna keep drinking or like your
moment on the porch so
i guess
you know talking about just change you
know because change is something that
sometimes you don't realize it's
happening until you have that distance
from it you're looking back
how
sp you you now at this age speaking to
not not necessarily like your younger
self
but like a younger dj in the same
scenario
sure how do you tell him to to hey man
don't forget to to see those flashes
don't forget to see those
those signs that are trying like because
there's this thing where it's like
uh was it like you you
what like a i'm trying not to say yolo
so bad right now god damn it
but like the you know like those moments
we're like bro i'm here for a a good
time not a long time and you pour
another shot
and like but but at some point you know
you're you've just done your life
doing that you've just lived your life
doing that so so how do we make sure
that
that young people who are in the music
industry who are maybe not djs maybe
they're musicians maybe they're
maybe they're just bartenders who
whatever we're in the scenario and it's
very easy to fall into these
these things where you're you're living
in the blur
right you don't see the change i i think
that
i mean for me um i
really try to get active there's two
things
at least in my mindset there's
activities
um that don't revolve around
you know partying so whether or not
that's
it's going to sound corny but you know
going on a hike or
um watching netflix with
with you're saying if another or um you
know if you got kids
you know for for me i was um coaching
you know so i coached soccer and i
coached basketball and and
um it's it's doing
activities that don't center around
using substances partying you know and
um you know i'll throw it out there the
the guys that you know drank guys and
gals that you know
partied in high school and then partied
out of high school and then
then they they're playing softball every
week
right in adult adult league and they got
big old cooler of beer
while they're playing softball and you
know obviously
beer is a social you know lubricant and
and you know it's accepted but like if
you're doing it
all the time and every activity that you
have
revolves around that aspect of it
like oh we're gonna have fourth july
party gotta have cooler beer
oh we're gonna go in camping oh gotta
have cooler beer oh we're gonna go play
softball
gotta have cooler beer oh we're gonna go
play cornhole gotta have cooler beer
you know there's nothing wrong with beer
i mean i trust me i
drink my fair share but i think that
that
if you want to break free from that
cycle
you need to find activities that don't
revolve around that yeah um i think the
second aspect is is that
you need to surround yourself with
with people who are genuinely
interested in your health and well-being
that's a big one and whether or not
you know i'm i'm very fortunate um it's
a lot of work but i'm very fortunate
to to be married for 15 years um so if
it's
a life partner um
that you know is is super important
if you are single and you have kids you
know if it's your
kids that you are building relationships
with and
and activities that do not involve
obviously partying
if it's being around creatives
that push you and that have an
expectation you know that
um you're gonna be at a certain spot at
a certain time and they'll call you out
on that type of stuff so if you go out
partying the night before
and i feel kind of sheepish bring this
up but you know you go you go
drink too many beers on on a saturday
night you know
like like i did last weekend and
you're supposed to have a podcast on on
sunday right
and uh with with a good friend and you
know
you text him or your good friend texts
you
because he's really looking forward to
doing the podcast
and it's something that you've talked
about been doing
you you know and then you have to text
him back at 7 30 in the morning because
he's excited he's up
he's ready to go he's expecting you
probably around 10 have a cup of coffee
get ready to go and you got to text him
back and you
you know you got to feel like a little
bit of a piece of you do because
you you got to say
yeah you know i drank too much last
night i'm really hungover i'm gonna be a
slug today
but what you should do is you shouldn't
like you should feel guilty you should
guilt is a good motivator right because
you let somebody down
um you know you try to make it up but
you're never going to get that back
you're never going to get back the the
excitement that that person
was giving you at 7 30 in the morning
and then you text them back at you know
nine and like i'm not gonna make it bro
you know you can't do that to somebody
too many times
until they they won't text you anymore
right
and so i think that it's you know it's
two things it's finding activities and
that was you know that was my i'm sorry
father i've sinned
session but um i think that there's two
things i think that there's finding
activities that don't 100
revolve around using substances and
partying and staying up all night and
you know the nightlife piece and i think
that there's
surrounding yourself with people that
help you
become successful humans and whether or
not that's
people that hold you accountable people
that you
respect and you don't want to let down
it's not always
someone that you know is your mentor
or someone who is you know like a
brother to you or what it may be but
someone that you're you you don't want
to let down or someone that you care
about and so you
you know check in on them and and um
i feel like i'm babbling a little bit
but
well i think that's that's how you
you know i i way back when i mean this
is
you know 25 or 20 years ago i had a dui
because that's just what happens when
when you live that lifestyle and you're
responsible and i went to
aaa meetings and i hated it because
everybody around me
was at the very bottom of the barrel you
know in the in their life like they had
hit
rock bottom and not that they're bad
people just they'd hit rock bottom
and i couldn't relate with them um
because i hadn't i hadn't lost anything
like i was you know i still had i can't
remember if we're engaged
or not yet either engaged or still have
the girlfriend
you know had supportive family um i
didn't lose anything you know i didn't
hit anybody i didn't
fortunately you know get in an accident
and kill anybody
or anybody else right so it was really
hard for me to be able to relate
um with the fact that i had a substance
abuse problem but
i was court ordered to go to these
meetings and
i couldn't relate with anybody and i
think
the the not the point because it was a
very long journey it wasn't like
overnight
um but things started getting better and
i was
able to um manage
if that's even the correct term things
better when i started
aligning myself with people that i
didn't want to let down
that i wanted to
have them be proud of what i was doing
and whether or not that was you know my
mom and dad
whether or not that was uh managers or
mentors at work
um i just i got in the mindset where i'm
like you know i don't wanna
i wanna be a good human um what i'm
doing now is
is not being a good human and
um i don't want to let these these
people down
right um well
well so i think those are all great
because i think that when you could lean
on other people when you can
there's this like just magnificent power
in allowing yourself to just for a
second
just for a minute just for a morning to
see yourself through the eyes of other
people because there's a lot of people
who
probably think that you're incredible
amazing you know like in
and when you can like when you can kind
of give yourself you know what like
you know don't don't touch your own horn
don't stroke your ego but like
when you can try to live up to what they
think that you are right
rather than just trying to like keep
that facade up
um i i wanted to back up a little bit
because and i don't have an answer for
this so we might have to stumble through
it
sure but uh and we are getting up here
in time so we'll we'll we'll get up here
with this but
um that morning after
the the sunday so for me
that's when the suicidal thoughts were
the heaviest
just you feel the guilt from whatever
you did the night before you feel the
guilt for like just because you feel
shitty you have zero serotonin
you have no access to any like logical
thoughts in your head right
um how how do we transfer
that guilt because the guilt for me what
what what i would like
anything that would happen for me would
be guilt shame
and and i would just just
feed it back to myself and i would just
i mean sometimes i'd have multiple days
of just like i wouldn't text somebody
back and i'm just like hating
myself and blah blah
i didn't allow that guilt to turn into a
motivator because
i think the the beautiful thing about
like the the human psyche is
is guilt and shame and that like just a
little bit of regret
um like listen you got to live your life
and you're not always going to show up
to every single meeting like
you're just living you're trying to
figure this out just like everybody
else's but
there is this i feel like now i'm able
to listen to like oh man i wish i did
that differently and i'm not
i don't i don't throw a pity party for
myself anymore i don't throw this
i don't stay in that i don't try to like
oh that feeling really hurts to think
about so i'm going to do whatever i can
to not think about i'm trying to keep
busy i'm going to try to
keep drinking or i'm going to try to i'm
going to do a line or i'm going to take
it take a hit a week so i don't feel it
or
whatever it is how do we take that
that morning after or maybe even the end
of the night when you go home
um because
because i'm trying to think of if i was
listening to this
like five years ago i think that i would
feel
i would i would vibrate with what what
you're saying
i would agree but i think that it would
hurt too bad instantly that i would
find ways that i'd say that that ain't
me sure um
so i guess and this is what i'm saying
like i have no idea how to transfer this
but how do we turn that guilt
into not a pity party not a hey it's
like don't hate yourself
hating yourself is not cool hating
yourself is not okay it's not
it's not um going to help you
uh but how do we transfer that that
gift of guilt and shame right to
like motivate her like well
i i think that you know i mean we can
we can continue to talk about this
weekend i think that's
that's appropriate um
you know sunday rolls around it's not
going to happen
feel guilty about it right um i know
that
and i feel guilty about it because i
know that you needed this as much as i
needed this
i needed it for other reasons you needed
it for other reasons right
and so i think that what you do
is you say okay
you basically raise your hand and say i
messed up right
like like i i know that
i messed up in whatever aspect whether
or not you had too much drink and you
threw up
you know on your friend's shoe or you
know or you said something
silly to you know your significant other
that you shouldn't have
whatever it is rather than just saying
focusing on you know what i'm a real
piece of
because all that's going to do is going
to turn it inward and you're going to
continue to
to say yeah you are a piece of and
you know you we should have you know
have a beer you know or just
reify that piece of shitness right don't
do that i think i think what you do is
you
you basically raise your hand and say
you know like i said you messed up
and you made a mistake and because
i care and love about that person or i
want to be a good human
or whatever the instance is that you
promise yourself that you're going to
make up for it now you know there's
some things obviously that you just
can't make up for
like if you do something and it's
so it's a doozy um there's no amount of
fixing that you're going to be able to
do on it um
but i think that a big part of
becoming
i hate to work use the word adult but
you know a
productive human being and a good human
being is
understanding that you're going to make
mistakes that
um there is nobody that is perfect
in this world we're all just trying to
figure this out
and i'm gonna let you know you know i'm
41.
um i still haven't figured it out and
i still haven't figured out what i'm
what i want to do
in life meaning you know as a job and i
have
a fairly decent career already um i
i think that there's just
i i don't feel like i've figured it out
although people
on the outside may look in and say man
you have it all together
so again i you know i'll go back to
you know that point in the night where
it's the end of the night
or you know it's the
7 30 in the morning you're cracking your
eyelids open you're like oh my gosh what
did i do last night why did i do that
you know
um i i think that
it's it's admitting that
it i'm not going to say the cliche
meaning that you have a problem
admitting that that you are that you
have flaws
that you are that you're not perfect um
and the only thing that you can do
honestly
to be able to address those flaws
is to try to be better
and you know whether or not that is the
the mindset that i take with the event
promotions that i do try to be better
each time
whether or not that's um establishing
new friendships and relationships
whether or not they're business or
just personal how can i make this
better and i'm going to tell you that
you know
drinking a bunch of alcohol and doing a
bunch a bunch of substances
doesn't isn't going to make things
better
and so um
i i think honestly it's it's a mindset
and it's a constant mindset of
how do i do things better like how do i
get better
right how do you know whether or not
it's i'm shooting a basketball hoop or
basketball or or
djing or establishing you know
friendships
or like okay i did this last time and
and it
it worked out okay but you know how do i
do it better next time
um but but again i'm
you know i i think we're kind of bumping
around on it
is if you make a mistake
if you mess up
as much as it might hurt went up to it
raise your hand tell the person you're
sorry
jake i'm sorry for missing sunday
okay and then and then you move on right
you don't and now you don't get to
apologize
over and over and over again yeah but
next time that happens it hopefully
won't happen
right and you know what in whatever
aspect whether or not it's that specific
story that you and i are lamenting on
or other aspects that's just low-hanging
fruit yeah it was not a big deal i
used just it was a big deal to me wow i
mean it was uh
as things were going in my mental those
both of those days you know
it's it's it's not a big deal but but i
i love that you were able to take the
the most recent um
experience and and put that put those
lenses on it i think that
i mean for for any like continuous
listeners of the podcast i'm gonna
just push in the old self-love thing
here i mean that's
to me before i discovered like caring
about myself and self-love
and like learning that i'm just living
through my ego and i shouldn't do that
right um like i wasn't able to like
even begin to forgive myself in the
morning
like in anything you do or it's like
dude i drove home up last
night i'm such a
piece of and you just like bury
that in you just
like even the thought starts to hurt you
and so you just like
do whatever you can and not like i'm
gonna try to go back to sleep right i'm
gonna try i'm gonna ignore my friend's
text
i'm gonna like whatever it is i think
that
you know this life can be so hard and
especially like
you know we're we're sack of habits
sometimes we get we get caught up in the
wrong habits and we get caught up in the
wrong
um decisions and sometimes we even get
caught up in just once in a while you
make a little mistake
whatever it is but i think that when you
give yourself a little grace in the
morning
you know and and own up to it and feel
that feeling of guilt and feel that
feeling of
of like okay i don't want to do that and
then maybe ask back to yourself like
uh ask back to yourself say oh that's
good
say say what what what
what is it about that that i didn't like
and how
how like actionable how do i avoid doing
that again and maybe
maybe the answer is as simple as like
man
i you know i want to have fun i want to
have some drinks but like instead of
having six beers i'm gonna have
five right you know like like whatever
it can be
to where next weekend or three weeks or
whatever it is when you start
you start getting down that same path
you can recognize your own patterns
right you know before you have to feel
that because
the the the gift of the morning after is
like you'd have lessons that you can
take or you know
but the thing is those lessons are
painful those lessons like when you
admit to them when you when
you feel them when you experience them
for for what they are
like i would get caught up in uh the
shame of it and
i would i would hate myself so much and
i would identify with that hate and i
would just like
try to try to add more mean words to
myself to make my like you deserve to
feel this you deserve to feel that well
and i
and i think spirals i think that you
know and i and i wanted to touch on this
you know because it's uh suicide
awareness month
um and i think it's important and i
i think that and i haven't shared this
with a
ton of people um i think that
the challenge that you face is you talk
you're talking about self-love right
and you have to you have to and i agree
i 100 agree with that statement is that
you have to
love yourself before you can love
anybody else
or you can allow other people to love
you because
once you have self-love you you
understand
how you want to be treated and how you
want people to
love you right if you don't even know
how to love yourself
how are you going to express and and
show other people how you want to be
loved right
so there's definitely that aspect um but
i think that there is
um there is um
you have to be self-disciplined um and
self-discipline for me
is um you have to
you know i'll go back to the common
theme of raising your hand admitting
that you made a mistake right
so um i will share a story um
if you're listening um it's um it's
maybe a trigger so um when i went to
college
um i went down to arizona um
parents paid for everything um shipped
me down there
and it was just a free-for-all it was a
party
and i had a really good time
and i wasn't very responsible at all
and i came back um
i'm back up a little bit so my um
my folks flew down and we got my
grades for the first quarter and i had
failed out of
every single class and
so um we flew back i visited
um and
i was um instead of
you know self-reflecting and saying how
am i gonna do better
and you know i really did mess up um
i drank drank like fish
and um
i was out in my parents
shop and even though i wasn't directly
saying i'm going to take my life
i was playing with with a handgun in a
way that
um that a mentally healthy
person i would not do and
um basically was um
i was playing with with with firearm in
a way that i shouldn't have
and the firearm went off
and i have a beautiful
reminder scar on the very front of
my top of my hairline where
i at the time it was explained to me
that it would have been a millimeter
closer
and it would have um not been as easy
um as as what occurred
and i remember um
walking into the house and um
calling up to my folks because they were
both sleeping
and um i have i'm obviously a
you know wound on my head and and
there's
blood all over the place and and calling
up to my
folks and and letting him know that i
had um shot myself
and i'm gonna tell you that it's um
it's a very humbling experience when
when your
father you know you're you're
i remember i think it was 19 and your
father
um is holding you um in his arms
and you know it wasn't a fatal wound
um i was very lucky um it wasn't beyond
anything than a graze
um you know and he's he's crying and and
so
um it was
um you know it was an
eye-opener um it didn't it didn't set me
on my path
um of being a good human yet
um but it is for me you know very much
a a reminder of
um what not to do and
what that not to do was is
it revolves around um
not taking uh personal responsibility
um for what i was doing
and at that time i was partying
and not going to class and not studying
and not doing um things that
um you know we're going to help me be a
better human
we're going to make people that that
loved me
um you know my blood love but
um also other friends to have them
um be proud of
you know the efforts that i was doing
[Music]
it was
it's you know it's very much a corner
cornerstone of of
how i operate um but it's
it's important for me to remember that
at that time
i was not being um
responsible i was not taking
steps towards being healthy and i didn't
take personal responsibility for the
fact that i had failed out of school
and you know that i had blown all this
money that that my
folks had paid for and um
so it like i said it it didn't
after the instance happened and and you
know there was a
um there was lots of doctors
appointments after that
and lots of therapy um
you know it didn't change unfortunately
who i was at that time
um which people from the outside
reflecting in maybe would think you know
how could i have done that and then
still just continue down that path
um but it's you know
two things um from from sharing that
that story publicly is that
um there is
never anything in the world that
um is ever worth um
not being here um
and the second thing is is that um
there there is um
importance in
taking acceptance for the fact that you
are making mistakes
and realizing that you are making
mistakes
and and how you can be better
to not make those mistakes i guess is
the point that i'm trying to make with
with that yeah man
that's powerful thank you so much for
sharing that that got to me man it's uh
that's super powerful for you to share
that i think that i think that
probably more people than you can
imagine can relate with
something similar along those lines just
the that's just
that's just one of them yeah i actually
have two attempts but
we'll we'll share the other one for
another day but it's maybe next podcast
yeah yeah it's uh that dude that like
just just imagining like you just you're
saying the word carelessness
you know being when
you i mean you're a very smart person
now i imagine you've always been
smart enough to know that you're
a handgun is the serious thing you know
there's some sort of
underlying weirdness
with that carelessness you know even at
that age you know and as someone who has
i've experienced my own um carelessness
with handguns myself with my own
suicidal thoughts
so um i mean
i think that a lot of times
there's something here like i i don't
want to get like spiritual religious or
like say god's knocking on the door
or any of that you know i i don't want
to miss anybody who that doesn't
resonate with but
you know sometimes there's signals
there's signs there's
there's things where it's like come on
man i
i want more for myself right i want more
for myself and i think that any listener
who has been in any sort of similar
situation like
you deserve to have that self-love
you deserve to say like if you get there
and and this has happened to you as
something similar has happened to you
you've gotten yourself in your own hands
careless handgun situation
listen listen to that voice that says
what's up here what's going on what am i
doing do i really want this
and i think that you know any
uh and i'm sure that anybody has been
um in that mindset
it's not even depth because you know
people's depressions are all different
and the amount of depression that
someone's in is
is a totally different story than
somebody else
and the amount of depression that that
you may be in is way different than
you know the experience that i had i
think that
what we can't discount though is that
it's it's extremely
difficult and challenging when you get
in that mind space
to get out of that mind space like you
don't
feel like anything that you do
or say is going to fix
what happened or what's happening to you
and
for me because that's a cornerstone of
how i try to now try to treat people
and why i reach out you know to people
that
i'm concerned about or that i care about
or that i love about or that i love
is i know what it's like when
you're in that spot and you don't
even though you're totally surrounded
like you know i don't have a broken home
i have
two parents and and you know we were
middle class and
and like i didn't have a bad upbringing
and so all those things even then
didn't make me quote successful
in what was happening and so
i think that for me because it's a
cornerstone
and it's not just to bring it up because
it's you know september and it's
suicide awareness month
it is literally a driver for me now i'm
not a counselor
okay i didn't go into that field um
just not who i am but
it it does drive
the relationships and the communications
and the type of communications that i
have with other humans
[Music]
because i know that there are times when
people are in that spot and nobody knows
it
and nobody knows it and
they don't say anything and then they're
not here
[Music]
and they can't see it
but other people see it i've had
multiple people that
that i have like really like they're
gone
like why yeah you know and from
from people who are close to not so
close just acquaintances
and you're like but they were such a
cool
person and and i think that it's
it's important to continually reach out
to people that are have been friends
for a very brief time to homies
and and friends that you've known for
years that you haven't talked to even if
it's a hey how you doing
and
ultimately as humans we all want to
feel like we're loved
and i it's it's a basic need it's it's a
basic need of mine
you know and i have a wonderful family
and i have i have you know wonderful
parents and and i know that i'm loved
but
when you have people outside of those
types of relationships that
make you feel like you are loved and
that you matter
um and that everyone wants to feel
special
whether or not we're djing and we're
right whether or not um
i mean everybody wants to feel special
and i think that
i honestly feel like
everybody everybody deserves to be you
know
told that they're special and and feel
like they are special
we can edit out the the
the loop that i just did there but no it
makes sense man
um and as humans if
if we can share the fact that we care
about people
and love people and there's so many
obviously
different layers of of love you know my
love for my wife is very much different
than my love for
you and kelly but and i don't think that
there should be
there should be anything that's weird
or awkward about telling somebody that
you
that you care about them and that you
love them
so well i mean just you know speaking on
our friendship
you know i don't want to dive too far
into it but i i happen to be
going through yeah i
i i have
dude like one text could mean so much
and and
there's you know just for example um i
mean you
you texted me you you've you've had
times where you texted me
just checking in just checking in every
few days where you know i'm going
through a few things
um just because i have been vocal on
this podcast and in my life and
and just with people because i think
that's important i have been vocal about
my own suicidal issues
um in in the past my own my own i try to
wear my depression on my sleeve because
i really think that it'll help
other people um and
like i truthfully truthfully mean it
when i say like
when someone texts me and says hey i'm
just checking on you like
that's everything that's everything like
they don't need anything
yeah they don't want anything yeah just
checking it or or even if
even if you know and i'm just the type
of person who i'm open to talk about
those things so
you can full-on say like hey bro i'm
just checking on you you good today on
your mental but some people aren't
aren't that far in and maybe maybe what
they need is just a
and you know your friends listener maybe
they need just to like
hey buddy what's up how are you right
what are you up to you watch
this like or send them a clip or you
just just contact them
just just reach out to them um i think
that
you know this
life can get super hard and
especially nowadays i mean dude suicide
rates are higher than they have ever
been and it's just
it's just too high and i think that
these conversations have to be
in the light they have to be the the
fact that people
struggle is okay like
and we have to be able to reach out to
each other in whatever way
um that that can be beneficial to that
other
person well i mean i feel like you know
i kind of got
together in life right
and i'm going to tell you 2020
sucks
i mean from from political to to you
know covet to
now we're in the pacific northwest and
you know we have wild
wildfires all over the place breathe
outside yeah we have uh you know entire
towns that are being decimated
um the entire west coast is on fire um
i don't want i don't want anybody to
feel like they are alone in thinking
that
2020 is a hot dumpster fire um
and it it has it i mean for me it's it's
been
it's been tough um you know
covid um i'm i'm able to still work
fortunately um but
i know that there's a lot of people out
there that aren't
or are not working it aren't aren't
working as
much and um
it could just seem like everything is
going
sideways and and i and me
i have what i think is all the plates
spinning if you want to think of it that
way
um and things are going good and i feel
like things are just going sideways
yeah so it's
i don't know yeah i mean i i think that
but i think that reaching out to people
and continuing
you know conversations and the fact that
we're all
majority of us at least in corporate
sense are working from home you know or
people aren't working as much
and so maybe they're isolating um
i think it's really important to
continually establish
and you're right it's just a text you
know hey how you doing
um and it could be you know i like
texting you because it can be hey how
you doing and then
you know you give me a very thoughtful
multi-paragraph
well he asked me how i'm doing here i'm
doing you know yeah well well the reason
why i do that brian is because i used to
everybody
because people tell like i get a text as
i'm
literally physically curl up in a ball
having a panic attack that's lasted five
hours now
right and i would text someone back and
like i'm good bro how are you
and now now i'm like you asked how i am
and you know
today i'm you know me i'll text back and
i'll say
you know to be honest man i've had a
pretty rough morning right and here's
why and here's what's going on
but i'm doing okay because this or
whatever it is but also if i said
if i just sent back not good you'd
probably say i'm on my way
right you know or whatever it is and i
have to i've had um
in in i'm i'm i'm going through some
things now but i
like i i had a homie um that i
uh he sent me a message i sent him a
message back and and he just
he just hits me back with how could i
help right and i didn't respond
and then 27 minutes later he's calling
me
right and he's any and i answered and he
says the same thing how can i help
right and and then he he talks to me and
and he
in some senses he just he talks and and
makes me listen
you know and i think that
this life for everybody can be
super difficult and i think that there
is
you know back to that guilt and that
shame i think that we feel
guilt and shame for not doing super well
sometimes
yeah i think that especially when we
have a facade of always doing well
and i think that the power behind
any level of friendship that you have
trying to i think that pushing against
a friendship by being too personal is
the coolest thing you could do like like
there was a point where you said if if
i'm overreaching you let me know
right i care about you and i i send even
a longer text back like you can't even
imagine how important this is that
you've texted me
you know and and and you know as
just from my experience by again i know
not a lot of people are
are like this and it's super okay you
don't have to wear your heart on your
sleeve you don't have to wear your
depression or suicide thoughts on your
sleeve
you can keep it to yourself that's okay
you know you don't keep it to your close
friends you don't have to tell everybody
i understand
but for me
because i've been vocal about in the
past um
there's this it makes me uncomfortable
in a weird sense because i'm like
oh you know now now every time i go
through any sort of hardship
everybody thinks i'm gonna want to die
sure but there is this
beauty of like the true essence of like
like people care about you and
that's the truth and
like people reach out in
in inadvertent ways like so i don't know
man i i think that
with suicide with depression with
anxiety with all this stuff
it's confusing and it's there's this
stupid
corny embarrassment with it um and
that's just all part of it but i think
that
i want to do anything i can to talk
about it and
um and make it not corny and make it any
if you listen or if you have a friend
who's suicidal you just don't understand
it
that's okay you don't have to understand
it like but but
all you have to do is like have you
experienced pain before yes
what's the worst pain you've experienced
like think about it cool
uh well just all you have to know is
that if you have someone who's like
experiencing suicidal thoughts or a
friend who's experiencing depression in
somewhat of a way
they're experiencing pain and you've
been through pain before right and if
there's anything that you can do
to let them know that they're not alone
let them know that that what they're
feeling is is okay
um talk them through whatever they're
going through there's no rule book
you know this society that we have isn't
prepared for how much suicide there is
we aren't prepared for how much
everybody's depressed how much
i mean who knows how many more people
are going to be depressed because of
this
this pandemic and all these young kids
who are going to be stuck at home and
they're not even able to hang out with
their friends and they're just
we've got to be able to stumble through
the conversations and i think that
there's no right way to do it
so whatever way that you think is the
right way to do it to reach out to your
friends or if you're the person who's
experiencing any sort of suicidal
thoughts
i i'm the i'm the frantic guy seriously
you're the frantic guy
the frantic yeah i i will are you okay
yeah are you sure can i see you face to
face
like let's go do something right um i
you have to be and you're not you don't
have that level of friendship obviously
with everybody that you know but
you have to be that engaging because
you're right you'll get in a situation
where
you know they'll just bluff you yeah i'm
good bro
right no are you really good like i
haven't seen you for like six months you
know what's going on
yeah you know like the when
when other people when when you have
friends that
that make sudden changes
like you don't seem anymore right and
it's not because
maybe they're working or or they've
moved away they're just
they're isolating right and
those are the telltale signs you need to
you know push harder
i mean you know i asked permission to
push harder
with you and i and you're like yeah i
love it let's you know you're talking
but you you have to if if people are
if you're getting one-liners back when
you're asking
pretty engaging questions you know those
are those need to be red flags for you
right and for me you know i turn
because it i reflect back on my like one
of my cornerstones i'm just like
okay we need to talk about this there's
something wrong you know
there's not wrong i guess isn't the the
term that i want to use but
something doesn't seem to be 100 healthy
enough yeah yeah
yeah you feel you you sound off you feel
off
you're making off decisions you know
what's going on
yeah and some people are going to talk
about it you know um
some people open up about it some people
will be like you know i
got some personal stuff going on and i'm
seeing somebody about it
you know right and then and that and
that's what they'll leave you with
and i i know i've already emphasized it
but
the way that i talk about my personal
experiences
with suicide the way that you just have
that's
pretty uncommon it's massively uncommon
it's uncomfortable for people it's very
uncomfortable i mean and it bring like
you speaking about your experiences just
like
i mean it brings me pain from my own
experiences and just thinking about you
as my friend but
i think that there's no wrong way to go
about it
and listener again whether you're the
friend or you're
or you're feeling a little down on
yourself you know whatever you're going
through
is all right you know you're on an
escalator you're just you got to ride it
out right you know it's
it's it's going to be okay i mean
there's no
wrong or white right way to approach
this next thing
but don't ignore it you know don't don't
don't you let
that side of your mind tell you that
you're not worth something
like that's some in in a lot of
times you can have a friend who will
just tell you a few simple dorky
sentences and it's enough to remind you
like
all right yeah that's true man i'm
i'm all right i'm good
like i'm worth it or or whatever it is i
think the other
and it's a challenge and it's and it's
hard um
is wanting to ask for help
yeah you know getting getting in that
spot where
you know you don't think anybody cares
or and
and i think that it's you feel like a
burden maybe
yeah um and you know oh well they're
you know they've gotten married and
they've got kids and so
you know they've got their own life now
and i'm just you're right i'm
you know i'm gonna be perceived as a
burden
and you know
we we can we can talk about we can talk
about
being responsible for decisions
you know raise your hand you made a
mistake
but you can also admit that you need
help
and that could be in multitudes of
different ways you know it could be
two weeks before an event production
you're like i feel really overwhelmed
and i need help from you guys can you
guys help me out and you know of course
both of you guys were totally like
without even skipping a beat yep what do
you need yeah
and had i not asked i would have been
totally yeah
i think that when we think of asking for
help i think movies or or something
when it pops in my head it seems like
asking for help means that
someone's going to take you on in the
psych to the psych ward or something
right like asking for help means that
you're drawing a line in the sand and
saying that i'm busted or saying that
i'm
i need help and i'm crazy and i'm
incapable of doing anything it's like no
it's not that like
whatever your level of asking for help
is is okay
yeah well and i think that it's and it's
hard
it's hard when you're in that spot to
have that awareness
and so if you have somebody that
you think that you feel is off like
things aren't going
correctly then i'm gonna tell you that
reaching out to them and offering them
help and maybe even being
not frantic isn't the correct term but
insistent
on that help like hey you know can i
help you out with this
and they're like no i'm good you know
i'm good and they
basically disappear being consistent
and you know whether or not that's
i don't know helping around the house or
mowing or
you know what happens when when you get
in those deep dark spots
is that you know you're not keeping up
on your
appearance or you're you know sleeping
all day
and everybody's depression experience is
totally different
from everybody else's so you know i'm
throwing out antidotes that
um taking somebody a cup of coffee
you know yeah i mean it's it's things
that
if they're not going to ask for help
then you know you can
there's little things that you can do to
be able to help them
that will hopefully establish that
communication
channel in order to be able to start
having those types of conversations
yeah and and i think that the biggest
thing is if you're experiencing any sort
of
or of that is like it's not who you are
man
it's not every it's not every like your
thoughts are not who you are you're the
observer of thoughts and
and you like if you're experiencing
these things
your mind will try to come up with
reasons to justify why and it'll try to
tell you why you should still feel bad
and why you should continue doing it or
whatever they'll try to be mean to you
and i think that
if that's going on you just you just
have to
say okay something something seems to be
off here
and you don't have to even answer that
you don't have to but well well what is
it what did i do and blah blah and try
to solve those things like okay
something's off here
and then you can get present and kind of
look around like what's what's going on
here
um i think just man
it's like what do they always say like
like people who who take the dive like
you know you you
you the people who have survived jumping
off the bridge they always say the
second they let go of that bridge rail
it's like they they regretted it right
they're like i realized in that moment
like oh yeah
that's i was just caught up in that that
thought i was just caught up in that
that thought that's not me you know well
and i think that
i think that it's important to
be able to establish for me personally
establishing a health check so
you know one aspect that i still
um i don't call it really a battle but
i have to be self-aware about it
is i really like beer right
and i know that if i drink too much beer
multiple days in a row then i start
start getting negative
type thought patterns right same same
and so
for me um you know
two beers on this night and then the
next night is like two beers and then
we're in the weekend and then we're
having
okay now we're gonna have four well
that's three days in a row right
and then i'm like oh well i'm hungover
and so
on sunday i'm going to go ahead and have
a beer just to be able to take that edge
off right well then i'm going back into
work on
and for me it's basically health checks
right
so um day three of that
and that's definitely not a binger but
day three of
drinking beer i
i basically start throwing red flags i'm
like wait hold on
right like i don't feel good about
myself um
because you've listened to yourself and
yes you know i'm being
being negative or being angry or you
know i'm being
short with people around me and
you know i'm like okay i need to take a
break
or i need to do something different or
or
whatever the instance is um
i think that it's really important to
set a health
baseline you know both mentally and
physically but
but definitely mentally like okay
and and it's and it's a lot of
self-reflection but it's
okay this is me happy and these are
things that are happening around me but
you know right now this is what it feels
like to be
happy and i have a baseline and i have
healthy relationships with friends and
family and i'm not
drinking or using and i'm going to the
gym
and things are good in my world whether
or not you know
works going good or or other things
right
like i feel good about myself and the
relationships that i have
and that what i'm working on that's your
baseline
but if you are you know you have three
days that you're
that you've been drinking or you know
you
s something bad happens at work or
relationship
and you're three days in and all of a
sudden you
are reflecting inward and you're like
okay
and we talked about this earlier i feel
off like there's things that
aren't right i don't i'm not
happy um and there's there's
opportunities in that instance to
whether or not you've written down i'm
gonna
this is gonna sound cliche but lifelines
right like if if i'm feeling
bad um about things i'll go have
um a saturday cup of coffee with my dad
right and we'll go sit there and we'll
talk for 30 40 minutes if that
or if absolutely my mom if my dad's not
available
so it's it's little lifelines that that
i've established that
and they don't know that right it's not
like i've set an expectation like i'm in
danger and so
now i'm gonna go to this yeah um and
same thing with with
uh with my wife with my kids yeah um
is i will set little things that i do
when i'm starting to go down a path that
i recognize right and it's but it's hard
when you're
when you're at rock bottom or what you
feel is rock bottom
and so you know i want to share that
with your listeners is that
all of these things i have established
over a lot of years right you know i
have a ton of experience
um dealing with this stuff but
i think it's important that um you set a
baseline
of okay right now i'm in a good space
and i'm happy
um and and things are going well right
and then you're able to reflect back on
that of okay
and the cool thing is when you do that
if you get in a situation where
life isn't good and it's outside of your
control
right so like work let's say there's
external things that are happening at
work
you don't have any control over it
rather than
getting in a situation where you're
going to drink or use or
or be depressed or stop going to the gym
or stop
talking and having those communication
channels
realizing that the challenges that
you're having in this one area
are not able to be affected by you
then you can then really focus on the
other areas that
and it allows you to balance out and
make sure that you stay at that certain
baseline per se mentally
when it's things that you can't control
right
i will tell you honestly with kovid and
the gyms being closed
has been very challenging right like i
would i
not that i'm going to you know get
strong and and buff and be
beach bod ready um but there's there's
obviously
huge health benefits to going to the gym
and for me
going to the gym was a destination right
i have a hard time going on a hike or
walking around my property or or you
know lifting dumbbells in my house
i just i have to break it up enough
right right the personality for me is
that i have to have a destination to go
to to be able to go work out
yeah and so with a holy fine too that's
great
a lot of people like that and with kovid
not having that
ability that's one aspect of my baseline
that i haven't been able to do and so
that
you know it's i'm going to tell you it's
it's been challenging
um as with everybody that's been going
through this
so but i acknowledge and recognize the
fact that
i'm not going to the gym and i know that
that's affecting other areas of my life
yes so so you find other ways to make up
for i mean i like
it's it's it's interesting you bring
that up because that that kind of you
know the last
the last couple weeks for me um
we got back and and i'm a runner that's
a lot of my thing when i catch myself
slipping or i catch myself i'm like okay
well you know it's about i i'm getting
caught up with those thoughts that
that i know take me down the wrong path
and i've built this resilient
side of myself right because with time
and patience and in
work you can build those things up to
where you a lot even in those dark
moments you you have a little part of
you that can remember of like
okay you know i'm just getting caught in
the current of things and so i'll
usually go on runs
i'll go i'll run it out till i collapse
i'll do do whatever i can i'll put on my
motivational videos and
run through my headphones um but we've
had the smoke
the last right and so i haven't been
able to but
what i've been doing is saying yes to
every opportunity
i i typically i like to kind of chill
with myself the most i can you know
i love my friends so much but i'm just
i'm an introverted person i
enjoy my alone time um but because i'm
not able to run
i think that uh one thing that i have
been doing is making sure i say yes i'm
like my friend's like hey i'm gonna come
pick you up i'm like okay yes sir
yeah or or i would avoid phone calls
typically
right and now like the last i know that
i haven't been running i haven't been
able to
go out and do my hikes yeah it's very
like
if i can go out and do like a 10 mile
solo hike
i come back and i'm just refreshed and
i'm like a newborn person i feel
great but there's so much smoke
right now that i wouldn't even be able
to get a few miles in without my lungs
hurting so
right um it's interesting because i
think as you're talking about i'm kind
of realizing like
man i really actually have like answered
my phone and texted people back and hung
out with friends
way more than i normally would in this
sort of like you know a little bit sad
situation
um so yeah i think just like listening
to those signals
of like doing something
right and i i really like what you said
like that like change of scenery
like is you know going to the gym like
it's different lighting
it's different sounds it's different
music it's a different like
even sometimes that social setting puts
you in like a different mental state
um yeah i i think getting out of it
because you know
we get so caught up with those those
nights those like those like where
you're just like you don't know what
else to think and
you just think that everything that your
mind is throwing at you think that's all
you
but then you get a different state um
tony robbins talks about a state change
all the time and that's probably a lot
of what that is like
even if that means you you're like okay
i'm oh man i just spent an hour
spiraling in my own head well how about
i stand up right now and i yell as loud
as i can and i do
50 push-ups and i you know i run from
the edge of my living room and back and
and 25 times whatever it is get in a
different state
and i think that's that has a lot of
power to kind of spark that like
who is the person in your head who even
said like oh
we're doing that thing again right let's
not do that it's okay brother
like you know that little like that
little positive narrator in your head
right like feed him and sometimes a
state change the physical body
movement change is enough for that or
again like i said like
answer your friends calls and they say
we're gonna go get coffee and you say
i don't want to but yes sir you
know like
and i like it even this morning i had i
don't i don't like phone calls super
early in the morning normally that's my
time
right but i know right now i could use
some some pep talk so i answered the
phone call and pretty much i had i had a
friend who's been very great to me um
like i said talk at me right and it was
i got off the phone and i felt motivated
as i felt great you know so
i think just man those lifelines
take those lifelines and you deserve
those lifelines
they're there for you you know yeah and
but i think you gotta you know from the
outside so we're talking about
self right but but i think as
an outsider to other humans
you need to let people know
that you are a lifeline like
i would i would hope that you know all
of my friends
um no matter who they are
and what stage in life they are would
feel like
if i called toasty that he'd be there
for me
whether whether or not it's you know i
hate to say this but financially
like if i was going through a hard spot
like if i needed 20 bucks
today as small as that
is you call brian right um if i just
need somebody
to listen to me cry for 30 minutes on
the phone
like that i think that that's you know
we're talking about a lot you know a lot
about depression
but i think that you know as people who
maybe aren't depressed in their in their
current
life you need to reach out to other
people
and let them know that dude if you need
anything right anything
you just let me know and that's within
reason i mean i'm not yeah yeah i'm not
gonna go
you know cap somebody for you but i mean
i might embarrass dead body
right i mean i got access to a backhoe
but
but i think that that's you know you're
talking about lifelines i think it's
really important to
it's two ways it's not just you know you
have your baseline you're like you know
what i'm good
but i need to plan ahead and if there's
something that happens then i need to be
able to
call so and so right you need people to
reach in
to be able to show you that sign that
okay those people are my go-to people if
if there's a problem
and so i think it's an i think
depression is is
very multifaceted and it's very complex
um and there's a lot of different
factors and everybody's situation is
is 100 different from everybody else's
situation
but i think that there's some common
things that that
people can do realizing that
even if you have mild depression you
don't even re
i think it goes back to just being being
a good human
and and trying to you know be a good
person
and and help out other people
and you may have have never experienced
depression
right and that would that's amazing
um but you need to
i would encourage people that haven't
been to those depths
that is listening to this podcast and
saying
gosh brian and jake are absolutely crazy
i've never
i've never had any of those types of
thoughts right
i would encourage those people to
and it's it's not you don't need to post
on facebook hey
if you think about killing yourself i'm
here for you
that's not going to help anybody right
you need to be able to establish
friendships and communication paths to
other people that
when they are in that situation and they
do get to that point
and nobody knows it and they're shutting
down
that you are there to either help pick
them up
or be able to realize
and recognize that they are in a
in a spot that that they need someone to
kind of
yes pick them up yes yeah and it's two
ways
because sometimes it's going to be like
you know in our situation
in jake and i's relationship jake's
going to text me and say hey
i could really use a cup of coffee right
and that's probably going to be the one
percent
i'm just being honest with you know how
how i know things work right
99 of the time it's gonna be me texting
jack and say hey
what are you doing oh just hanging out
wanna go get a beer no
well what are you working on nothing
really and
and me asking those questions and
recognizing
okay you're not working on anything
we're friends
yeah i know if you're not working on
anything it's different it's weird we
normally like to go
have a beer maybe i don't present it as
a beer maybe i present it as
you know a coffee because i know jake
really likes coffee
and he still doesn't bite on it then i
know that as a friend
that's a flag and and that's when you
have you know the person that calls you
up 27 minutes later and
yeah gives you a pep talk so
i think that it's important to
i know a com common theme you know for
me and
you know a lot of your core is being a
good
human and establishing those
communication channels
with with other people and
you know being there for people that i
don't know
we just we live in a society that's
that's
you know it's it's weird yeah that's
that's weird that's that's all i can you
know kind of
summarize it as because
you know growing up as as as men we're
supposed to be strong right not ask for
help
and um it's it's
disheartening to see um men that i
you know love and respect that don't ask
for help because they want to try to be
strong
and and um maybe
need help whether or not it's even and
it's not even like you're going to
do everything for them you're just going
to give them a call or a text
dude i mean i'll summarize it with this
as humans we need each other
and that's okay it is it's so okay we
need each other
and that's okay like it's so okay to
like
just say i need i need somebody right
now
if somebody's throwing you it's throwing
your life raft it's okay to grab it
right and it's uh like it's okay to
whatever level you are at like whatever
level of encouragement or help or
assistance
or whatever you need or can offer
is okay like like uh
we need each other and it's okay i mean
that that's the bottom line dude i
i uh man this has been super great
this is like i'm so glad that we went
here yeah i
i really i truthfully believe in my
heart that that this is gonna help
people
um that that it'll i mean even just
having conversations that people are
afraid to stumble through
um we both certainly stumbled through it
ourselves we did
um but i just listener
you matter uh
that's the bottom line you matter we've
got to be able to like reach out to one
another
we've got to be able to especially in
these times like right now
is crazy man it is and it's okay to
feel whatever feelings that you're
feeling you don't have to feel bad about
them um but we we've got to reach out to
one another
now especially so um toasty i want to
thank you for being my friend i want to
thank you for giving me something to
creatively work on with glow in the dark
i want to thank you for teaching me
anything you teach me even
inadvertently just even i'm i'm always
dude i'm the type of person that i'm
always i'm just like that that we were
talking about that dj's
every song he plays he's glancing up
like who's tapping their foot okay they
don't like that genre they like that
song they
okay they want they don't like 2010s
okay they want newer whatever
we're analyzing i'm the type person that
i'm learning from everybody at all times
i'm glancing around i'm trying to say
like how can i
be better no you know how can i how can
i learn from all of my friends and you
teach me
a lot so i want to thank you i want to
thank you for sharing your personal
experience
um and i want to
loop it right back
glowingthedarkevents.com uh
also uh can you just let everybody know
where
to find your dj mixes and such sure
sure so i'm on uh soundcloud so it's
just uh dj toasty
all the socials are are dj toasty so
twitter
uh instagram uh instagram we have some
kind of fun behind the scenes
type stuff that's gonna be getting
posted this week
uh for glow in the dark uh dgtostie.com
but don't go there because i haven't
updated
quite a while a week yeah so
no i i i appreciate um you know the the
cool thing with
with getting engaged with uh creative
people
is it um it
it excites me and and i think that it uh
you know it helps me be more creative as
well
and um with glow-in-the-dark events
and uh jake and and kelly's uh
involvement as well um it's just it
breathes life
into things that you're trying to create
and do
and you know all the different
perspectives and experiences
and and it just it's the collaboration
is is amazing so i really appreciate you
having me on
appreciate you as a friend um and i
appreciate all the help that you did for
glow-in-the-dark i think without your
involvement
um it wouldn't be what it is so
well thank you man that's that's great i
i had a great time doing it um i had a
great time doing this podcast dude i'm
glad we got to talk about this thanks
listener
listen man you're worth it whatever
you're going through it's all right
whatever your friends are going through
you just let them know it's all right in
whatever way that means to you there's
no wrong way to go about this just
stumble through it man we're not we're
not perfect just do what you do what you
feel is right and
you're gonna be all right and one last
thing relax your shoulders
if you haven't drank much water today
drink a little bit of water
just relax you're okay look around get
present
you matter and if it helps i'm sending
you a big ol hug
take care of yourselves and saturday
september 19th
glow in the dark come see us dj and play
some electronic music get some friends
out
hang out with them jam out have some fun
we'll see you later take care
[Music]
knowledge is power
you